<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-25T21:20:09-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">recollectives</title><subtitle>a blog by kelly luo</subtitle><entry><title type="html">i need to get my story straight</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-05/all-of-a-sudden-i-miss-everyone" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="i need to get my story straight" /><published>2020-05-25T20:48:30-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-25T20:48:30-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-05/all%20of%20a%20sudden%20i%20miss%20everyone</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-05/all-of-a-sudden-i-miss-everyone">&lt;p&gt;It’s jarring to wake up one morning and realize the world has shifted on its axis. The collapsed, insular worldview of a college campus seemingly explodes overnight. The fairytale never gets its happy ending, the music stops, and the screen cuts to black.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Years from now, I wonder what I’ll say about what happened. If I’ll have more perspective and sympathy, if I’ll be even more bitter and vitriolic. That it was the kind of sweeping emotional turbulence that shakes up a generation and loses them to the current. That we never quite recovered because time heals all wounds except the ones it inflicted. That none of us woke up from the nightmare where the incongruities and uncertainties broke us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Left us disoriented, wandering, directionless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spring has almost molded into summer by now. Once upon a time, we were untouchable. We were seniors, so close yet so far, and we weren’t ready for the world as much as it wasn’t ready for us. The fabled day of Commencement, one day in late May 2020, circled on calendars and printed on notices. A storied tradition to celebrate soon-to-be college graduates coming of age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, the axis shift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the details of our reality now would sound fictitious in another timeline. We were robbed by circumstance, a cruel form of emotional grand larceny. The things we lost in the dissonance. No time, no people, no celebration, no goodbyes; nothing but get out and go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Virtual will never be a substitute for the real. The nuance is lost: the coarse grain of paper in your hands, the loud blare of the band in your ears, the frantic adrenaline of the heartbeat in your chest. I used to cautiously hope that there would be an escape hatch. The promise of people gathered in the same physical place once again. Promises, like all those that came before it, are empty. It was easier to keep hope alive in March, when the bandage had first ripped off and the wounds were fresh and stinging. Now they’ve started to scab and heal over anew, nature’s way of protecting us against more trauma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re young, everything matters. What may seem ordinary in retrospect becomes amplified and vibrantly colored in our memory; that’s everything our obsessive minds care about inside of our self-important bubbles. Graduation is a lot like that. Once again teetering on the cusp of youth and adulthood, bracing for impact. Soon thereafter, senior year didn’t matter; then our grades; and lastly commencement. Twenty-one years of life collapsed into a single space alongside everything that mattered to us up until now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The strange comedy I find in all of this is that I had materially orchestrated my entire life to build up to this. One academic uphill after the other so I could claim this moment as mine. The moment I would become a college graduate with the pomp and circumstance that only an achievement like this would be worthy of. The moment that will never come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won’t ever have this memory to hold onto. How I woke up that morning feeling anxious and restless as I donned my cap and gown. How the late May sun was warm on my skin as we filed into the Theatre to exultant fanfare. How that photo of me and my family holding my diploma was a silent hope across generations finally brought to life. My heels sinking into the soft grass; bright, beaming smiles on our faces; and the backdrop of historic brick buildings that were never built for people like us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can only construct an imagined pastiche of what I think it was supposed to be. A false memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a romantic at heart. I have lofty, wide-eyed ideals about the world and try to sculpt the forces of my life to those presuppositions. I came into college with a lot of expectations, and I cycled through college with constant grievances about how Harvard never met those expectations. A litany of would-haves and should-have-beens: it wasn’t what I wanted; I would be happier elsewhere; I wish I could do other things. I thought I would have a lot of regrets about the things I did and didn’t do during college when I got to the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I’m finally at the end, I’m really at peace. An eerily quiet, pleasant sort of calm. I don’t have this urge to wish for a time-turner and search for a reset button for freshman year. I’m grateful for the experiences I got to have and the people I got to meet and the things I got to learn. It wasn’t everything, but it was something. Having that, and suddenly realizing how easily everything can be stolen from you, makes you treasure the parts you can keep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this chaos has given me clarity. (A lot of confusion too, but a certain lucidity in the madness.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought I would have a lot to say when I got to the end. I thought of the melodramatic goodbye conversations I would have, the handwritten letters and messages with promises to keep in touch, and the personal essays I would write to catalogue the years into succinctly summarized takeaways and lifelong learnings. Over the course of senior year, I started workshopping those words in my head: the goodbye gifts, the tearful dinners and departures, and the apocalyptic preparation for the last time I would see most of these people. When the end came, there were no words left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of us had words, really. There was the inescapable sense of grief, the kind that overwhelms you at first and slowly buries itself deep inside you and never fully leaves. The kind of grief that resurfaces in unexpected moments: an old forgotten memento, a photo from a happier time, an echo of a name that becomes the refrain of somebody that you used to know. A loss you can’t shake out because its claws have sunk in deep and every time you look up, you realize you’re still bleeding. Open wounds, fresh salt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was in mourning. There wasn’t much to say because all the poets and songwriters and artists had said them before, and there wasn’t time to fill in the blanks with everything I wish could say in those final moments. I couldn’t eulogize my time at Harvard. I still don’t think I can. I grieved, and I’m not sure if any of us will ever stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing about this was perfect, not in the way we had envisaged with our romantic ideals of a spring still to come. It was complicated, excruciating, and if you really read between the lines, traumatic. The weather wasn’t warm yet and the Massachusetts winter hadn’t seen its last snow. The sun had made its first appearance the week before, the rare glimpse of sunshine that makes even the bitterest of cynics dare to hope again. With 3.75 years behind us, the last 0.25 were supposed to be the most precious. These were the auspicious times when were going to forge our lasting memories of college, a few promised weeks of pure and unadulterated freedom. There were lists of things to do one final time or before time was up, but we all thought we would have the time to do it. The spring was sacrosanct. We had paid our dues and it was the moment to collect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boston is the beacon for lost souls. Every fall, a pilgrimage of bright-eyed seventeen and eighteen year olds eagerly land on campus to make their mark on the world. They descend upon the brick and cobblestone of the historic city with their bulky suitcases and fantasies of freedom. Pilgrims on the shore of Plymouth Rock. They are adults yet, still earnest and hungry with a hopeful dose of naiveté.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of us will leave Boston and return immediately; we begin our careers and post-grad dreams in the same city that shaped our present. Some of us leave and come back years later; we return as aged-up versions of ourselves to embark onto the next phase of our lives. Some of us leave and never come back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have rooted ourselves to the heart of a place for four years, and these institutions have become a fundamental facet of our identity in our young adulthood. To suddenly displace us with an email at 8:00am one Tuesday morning challenges the systematic structures of belonging that have nurtured and comforted us throughout the years. Without a chance to repot and slowly acclimate to fresh soil, we have been uprooted. Pulled up our anchors and became unmoored wayfarers drifting at sea. There is no time left to indulge in the grandeur and ceremony of goodbye; closure will always be a privilege.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started writing this essay the night I left campus. I started—and then I stopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t write again for a while. For the longest time since then, I’ve had an urgency to write this. Had to let these words bleed out me like some sort of psychological bloodletting that would purge the sentimentality and sorrow out of my system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t always work that way, nor is it supposed to. This has been a blank page for me to dismantle my beliefs about college and attempt to reassemble them again to restore its meaning. It has helped me understand that this was a terrible, unfortunate thing that happened, but we each have our own complicated and incomplete feelings about it. I’m still trying to sort through my emotional rubble, and writing has been part of the convalescence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wouldn’t be an emotional essay from me if I didn’t quote &lt;em&gt;To All The Boys&lt;/em&gt; at least once, so as Lara Jean Song-Covey once said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Maybe my letters are like my exorcisms. My letters set me free. Or at least they’re supposed to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder if I’ve banished those spirits now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conventional wisdom told me you’re supposed to fall in love in college. We’ve all said we’ve loved a lot of things in this lifetime. People, places, passions. I don’t know if I was ever supposed to fall in love &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; college, but at the very least, college convinces you that you’re meant to find love. It’s the kind of love that keeps you up at night, that takes up precious space in the waking moments of your brain. You might not figure out everything you want from life in the span of four years, but you figure some of the things. The things that would break your heart if you had to let them go. The things that did break your heart when you had three days to say goodbye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;College also makes it easy to fall out of love. The easy disillusionment, the jaded regard for the new and old. That’s what Tennyson was referring to when he spoke of sorrow; what Winnie the Pooh had to say about goodbyes. The reason we feel the loss is because we had something to hold onto in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, you do fall in love. Not with another person, but—yourself. You learn yourself in a way you never could at sixteen. You start paying attention to yourself: the way you think, the way you operate and move about the world, and the way you feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m tired of my grief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone grieves differently; the stages progress unevenly. You mourn and lament for the time and experiences you’ll never get back (that you never had to begin with), and that sorrow weighs heavy on your shoulders. Soon, you’ll be buried with it. Emotional whiplash left each one of us reeling. I’ve done my share of dissociation and screaming and spontaneous crying and getting hopes up too high. Maybe this is acceptance at last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The things I miss, even if I don’t miss them now, were real once. They had physical form and took up corporeal space in my life. Endless, sprawling hours spent in the dining hall; conversations that lasted until the early morning; the way I always felt exasperated and exhausted and wonderous and so, so lucky to be here. I might not feel it now, but someday I will: all at once, all of a sudden, I will miss everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Light the candles and hold the vigil, scatter its ashes across the continents and seas—because college is over and it is never coming back. Pack up the people and memories into cardboard boxes the same way you did with your clothes and toiletries back in March. The things that mattered then won’t matter forever. Store away the sentimentality in a filing cabinet, because otherwise it can consume a person. I’ve always been good at this part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seal them into airtight compartments and carry those boxes into the attic of your brain. Let a thin layer of dust settle over the surface of your memory. One day—perhaps your fifth, tenth, or twenty-fifty reunion—you’ll find the courage to walk up that creaky wooden staircase again. Open a few windows, draw the curtains back, and let the light in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s your last morning, and you’ve already sealed up your last box and zipped up your last suitcase. You put down the half-used roll of packing tape and sit down at your desk and you suddenly start crying. And you can’t stop. (An older, maybe wiser, version of yourself will say it was grief; but for now, it’s the impenetrable silence in a vacant room.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You put on the saddest song you know and you sit in a bedroom that’s been stripped bare. The walls are stark white again, the command strips peeled down, and the mattress abandoned on the wooden bedframe. You take inventory of what remains: just you in an empty room, and it’s almost like you were never here. It would be so easy for the next person to move in and unpack their belongings and start this vicious cycle all over again. In the fall, someone will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you start writing. Letters are supposed to be your exorcisms, and maybe this will get that sinking feeling out of your chest. You seal them up and that’s it—that’s all the time you have left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I once read somewhere that going through college is like peeling a hard-boiled egg. We begin as a messy mixture of yolk and albumen. College submerges us into boiling hot water and pressure cooks us: the proteins denature and all the soft, amorphous parts of us at eighteen will harden by the time we’re twenty-one. These years change us irrevocably and the laws of biology say we can never go back to who we were before. College beats and pries apart every piece of us until we fracture and break open. Whatever sticks by the time the egg emerges from beneath the shell is the version of us that lasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of all the things that have stuck with you all this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;fin.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It’s jarring to wake up one morning and realize the world has shifted on its axis. The collapsed, insular worldview of a college campus seemingly explodes overnight. The fairytale never gets its happy ending, the music stops, and the screen cuts to black. Years from now, I wonder what I’ll say about what happened. If I’ll have more perspective and sympathy, if I’ll be even more bitter and vitriolic. That it was the kind of sweeping emotional turbulence that shakes up a generation and loses them to the current. That we never quite recovered because time heals all wounds except the ones it inflicted. That none of us woke up from the nightmare where the incongruities and uncertainties broke us. Left us disoriented, wandering, directionless.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">you made a slow disaster out of me</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-05/big-jet-plane" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="you made a slow disaster out of me" /><published>2020-05-22T16:24:42-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-22T16:24:42-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-05/big%20jet%20plane</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-05/big-jet-plane">&lt;p&gt;There are stories that begin on airplanes. A one-way flight to nowhere, or a round-trip back home. A metal vessel in the skies, floating and drifting and soaring. Think of the 12 km column of air and space that separates the thin carpet beneath your feet and the expanse of the Atlantic eager to catch you if you fall. The glimpse of icebergs and glaciers above the poles, endless blankets of white with jagged sawtooth edges. The way you feel claustrophobic in your seat, pressed up against strangers and food carts. Space that’s not yours, only borrowed. Shallower breathing that made your heart work faster and harder. Maybe you unbuckle your seatbelt and stand to stretch, eager for a breath of clean oxygen that has not been recycled twice over. Think of who you meet on that late night, early morning (time knows no bounds here) excursion for an extra bag of pretzels, hands outstretched for more. The way you reached to close that space, high up in the atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">There are stories that begin on airplanes. A one-way flight to nowhere, or a round-trip back home. A metal vessel in the skies, floating and drifting and soaring. Think of the 12 km column of air and space that separates the thin carpet beneath your feet and the expanse of the Atlantic eager to catch you if you fall. The glimpse of icebergs and glaciers above the poles, endless blankets of white with jagged sawtooth edges. The way you feel claustrophobic in your seat, pressed up against strangers and food carts. Space that’s not yours, only borrowed. Shallower breathing that made your heart work faster and harder. Maybe you unbuckle your seatbelt and stand to stretch, eager for a breath of clean oxygen that has not been recycled twice over. Think of who you meet on that late night, early morning (time knows no bounds here) excursion for an extra bag of pretzels, hands outstretched for more. The way you reached to close that space, high up in the atmosphere.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">it’s the third week of may</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-05/welcome-to-upfronts" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="it's the third week of may" /><published>2020-05-18T19:20:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-18T19:20:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-05/welcome%20to%20upfronts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-05/welcome-to-upfronts">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;why i’m worried about the future of tv.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;normally, this week would be tv upfronts season—but since that’s no longer physically possible, i’m worried the tv industry won’t survive these times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;upfronts are the splashy events held by major tv networks three weeks into may to showcase their upcoming show programming and garner advertising interest. it’s one of the most exciting weeks of my year (it’s heaven for a tv nerd like me) because we get a sneak preview of all the new pilots and shows that we can anticipate in the fall. the bulk of ad spend for tv happens “up front,” so most of the tv advertising money moves during these upfronts events and dictates the health of the network for the coming year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this year, we don’t have upfronts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;no upfronts means no confidence from advertisers and ultimately no ad contracts. this year, we don’t have new shows in the fall either. we’ve lost two months (and counting) of precious filming time. many current shows weren’t able to wrap up their current seasons. most new shows haven’t been able to film since their pilot pick-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the entire function of upfronts is predicated in these networks having new and flashy shows that might entice the pockets of advertisers. but given the uncertainty and destabilization of traditional film/tv production, nothing new will be coming in quite a while. thus, advertisers are disincentivized to spend. that’s *really* bad for network tv. this could potentially paralyze the tv industry and threaten tv has a platform for media and content. this forces the hand of traditional tv networks to think bigger and innovate; most significantly, shifting their viewers to digital surfaces (where many ads are also moving) or diversifying their offerings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so perhaps this is where streaming services and digitally-native studios completely unravel the traditional tv network. viewers focus their attention elsewhere. ad buyers fundamentally change their model. legacy media continues to sink.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">why i’m worried about the future of tv. normally, this week would be tv upfronts season—but since that’s no longer physically possible, i’m worried the tv industry won’t survive these times. upfronts are the splashy events held by major tv networks three weeks into may to showcase their upcoming show programming and garner advertising interest. it’s one of the most exciting weeks of my year (it’s heaven for a tv nerd like me) because we get a sneak preview of all the new pilots and shows that we can anticipate in the fall. the bulk of ad spend for tv happens “up front,” so most of the tv advertising money moves during these upfronts events and dictates the health of the network for the coming year. this year, we don’t have upfronts.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">two scoops vanilla, quarter-cup milk, maraschino cherry</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-05/are-they-always-destined-to-remember" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="two scoops vanilla, quarter-cup milk, maraschino cherry" /><published>2020-05-06T15:15:39-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-06T15:15:39-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-05/are%20they%20always%20destined%20to%20remember</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-05/are-they-always-destined-to-remember">&lt;p&gt;We love our milkshakes. It’s &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; drink that screams Americana, from the whipped cream and literal cherry on top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What is patriotism, but nostalgia for the foods of our youth?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I’ve been feeling very &lt;strong&gt;nostalgic&lt;/strong&gt;. The extended time at home has stirred that yearning for the past, for younger years. It’s inspired by the craving for the foods I grew up on, the music that filled my afternoons, and the stories that shaped the way I see the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In freshman year of high school, I wrote a research paper on the nature and conceptualization of nostalgia. There’s something called the &lt;em&gt;discontinuity hypothesis&lt;/em&gt; that researchers attribute to its psychological function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;discontinuity hypothesis&lt;/em&gt; states nostalgia is a means of coping with external threats; those who experience greater disruption or discontinuity in their lives will reflect upon their past more favorably than those who experience continuity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nostalgia is a coping mechanism. Our past offers solace and comfort that the tumult of the present cannot provide. It happens when the stability of our identity is compromised and restores our sense of self-regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our sense of self has been broken by our circumstances. We question who we are, what we want, why we are. The last time we had these same questions and were still grasping for answers, we were younger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To quote me at fourteen: &lt;em&gt;the juxtaposition of the past and present pieces together the puzzle of how you see yourself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We love our milkshakes. It’s the drink that screams Americana, from the whipped cream and literal cherry on top. What is patriotism, but nostalgia for the foods of our youth?” Recently, I’ve been feeling very nostalgic. The extended time at home has stirred that yearning for the past, for younger years. It’s inspired by the craving for the foods I grew up on, the music that filled my afternoons, and the stories that shaped the way I see the world.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">tales of the old and of the secrets we hold</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-04/the-tale-of-riverdale" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="tales of the old and of the secrets we hold" /><published>2020-04-20T01:24:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-20T01:24:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-04/the%20tale%20of%20riverdale</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-04/the-tale-of-riverdale">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;or: why riverdale could have been a much better show than it is&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite late night pasttimes is to watch YouTube compilations of &lt;em&gt;Riverdale&lt;/em&gt; scenes. They are absolutely excoriating. I have spent so many hours thinking about how &lt;em&gt;Riverdale&lt;/em&gt; could have been a better show. A much better show than whatever mess the writers are trying to pass off as melodrama with a cherry on top. To be frank, I haven’t seen an episode of Riverdale since the season 1 finale. I couldn’t get past the choppy pacing and chopped-up characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This show could have been incredible. It was sitting on a goldmine of potential, and its devoted teen audience has seen that storytelling potential waste away over the years. For however many more seasons the CW keeps renewing this show for, it won’t quite ever recover what the show could have been. Season 1, especially the pilot episode, felt ambient and precipitous. It felt like it was on the edge of something great and we were lucky enough to watch it unfold before us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my earliest pre-pilot predictions for the show, I had called it &lt;em&gt;Veronica Mars&lt;/em&gt; meets &lt;em&gt;One Tree Hill. Riverdale&lt;/em&gt; was supposed to offer the gritty, neo-noir teen detective elements of &lt;em&gt;Veronica Mars&lt;/em&gt; that painted a picture of a picturesque town with a seedy underbelly. That picturesque town was supposed to feel like it came out of the &lt;em&gt;One Tree Hill&lt;/em&gt; playbook, ordinary slices of life in a quiet, tangled suburb with a sprinkle of realism and a heavy dose of the overdramatic. We wanted simple stories with a self-indulgent teen drama twist. I genuinely thought &lt;em&gt;Riverdale&lt;/em&gt; was going to be the next great teen tv show. (These days, I’m still waiting for it). I was so prepared to love it—but if I’ve learned anything from watching years of tv, it’s that you can’t love the idea of something and expect it to be the real thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When The CW first announced it had picked up the pilot of &lt;em&gt;Riverdale&lt;/em&gt;, I was elated. It was time for another teen tv show to make its societal debut and ascend the throne. Since &lt;em&gt;Gossip Girl&lt;/em&gt; ended in 2012, there has been this vacancy for a &lt;em&gt;so bad it’s good&lt;/em&gt; show about teens in high school, making mistakes and falling in love and acting ten years past their age. The tv sphere lacked a show about teenagers where one of the characters wasn’t a vampire or werewolf, where the story still felt like it was grounded to a reality that could be ours. &lt;em&gt;Pretty Little Liars&lt;/em&gt; had gone off the rails by then and the fact that &lt;em&gt;Riverdale&lt;/em&gt; sought to follow in the footsteps of a pilot &lt;em&gt;whodunnit?&lt;/em&gt; probably should have been a hard first nail in its coffin. We were ready for the &lt;em&gt;Veronica Mars&lt;/em&gt; meets &lt;em&gt;One Tree Hill&lt;/em&gt; we were almost promised. What we’ve gotten instead feels paper-thin and forgettable, pure camp with bare substance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is so much that has gone wrong since the pilot that it is nearly impossible to rewind and find a place when it was still okay: (1) Grundy, everything about Grundy and writers who felt it was necessary to script yet another inappropriate student-teacher relationship on screen within the first hour of the show; (2) A messy timeline and poorly resolved killer that lost its credibility and shock value; (3) A serial killer named the Black Hood on the loose that makes One Tree Hill‘scrazy nanny Carrie plot mildly forgivable in comparison; (4) Jingle Jangle and all it’s alliterative nonsense; (5) a criminal biker gang from the wrong side of the town sketched as ambiguous antagonists and anti-heroes even when the PCH Biker Gang did it better; (6) the dysfunctional Coopers featuring dark!Betty and Chic and sinners; (7) The Lodges and so-called mafia influences and so-called evil that wears pearls and dark eyeliner; (8) honestly who let Jughead become embroiled with the Southside Serpents and make that the thesis of his character; (9) pretty sure Cheryl has PTSD and should talk to someone who can help her heal, but let’s reduce her to blood red lipstick and snippy one-liners instead; (10) and last and likely least, the conflicted Archie Andrews with half a death wish and puppy dog eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Riverdale&lt;/em&gt; could have been so much more if it started back at four kids sitting in a booth at Pop’s diner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A red-headed boy in a varsity jacket with a guitar slung on his back and dreams too big for a small town. A girl with blonde hair swept up into a high ponytail and fresh cuts on her palm and a burning fire to prove herself. A raven-haired girl with her demons on speed dial and a sharp longing for acceptance. A boy in a grey beanie with a burger in one hand and threads of the messy truth held in the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one shining moment, they were just kids before &lt;em&gt;Riverdale&lt;/em&gt; decided it wanted more.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">or: why riverdale could have been a much better show than it is One of my favorite late night pasttimes is to watch YouTube compilations of Riverdale scenes. They are absolutely excoriating. I have spent so many hours thinking about how Riverdale could have been a better show. A much better show than whatever mess the writers are trying to pass off as melodrama with a cherry on top. To be frank, I haven’t seen an episode of Riverdale since the season 1 finale. I couldn’t get past the choppy pacing and chopped-up characters. This show could have been incredible. It was sitting on a goldmine of potential, and its devoted teen audience has seen that storytelling potential waste away over the years. For however many more seasons the CW keeps renewing this show for, it won’t quite ever recover what the show could have been. Season 1, especially the pilot episode, felt ambient and precipitous. It felt like it was on the edge of something great and we were lucky enough to watch it unfold before us.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">the past is not a memory; it’s here</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-04/tigertail" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="the past is not a memory; it's here" /><published>2020-04-11T22:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-11T22:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-04/tigertail</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-04/tigertail">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tigertail&lt;/strong&gt; (dir. alan yang) was beautiful and poignant in the way you come home after a long day and allow yourself to slowly unwind in the silence. the film soaks in the quiet, recognizes that there aren’t always words to say what you mean, and visually renders those moments to speak louder than the script. it’s not a perfect film, but it is a poignant one. stop on any frame, and you see a sketch of yourself and your family in the mirror. these are a few things that made the film so resonant:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;recognizing that the homeland is so bright and vibrant, yet so unbearable. our parents, grandparents all started somewhere—some version of that same concrete house and barely-paved dirt road.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the monotony and loneliness of arriving somewhere new, unanchored. trying to put down roots in a place when you’re not sure it wants you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the sacrifices and choices we make so that someday we end up with a house on american soil. when does that stop being the dream? when did it stop for pin jui?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s pin jui sitting with a cup of tea in his dining room, alone in a big house. it’s angela with a half-eaten meal, wishing her father would say something. it’s the two of them together, framed side-by-side by a concrete block at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this film was alan yang’s way of producing a careful study of his own father, vivid in color and pensive in thought. it makes you want to stop and study your parents too; think about where they came from and what they have to say too.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">tigertail (dir. alan yang) was beautiful and poignant in the way you come home after a long day and allow yourself to slowly unwind in the silence. the film soaks in the quiet, recognizes that there aren’t always words to say what you mean, and visually renders those moments to speak louder than the script. it’s not a perfect film, but it is a poignant one. stop on any frame, and you see a sketch of yourself and your family in the mirror. these are a few things that made the film so resonant: recognizing that the homeland is so bright and vibrant, yet so unbearable. our parents, grandparents all started somewhere—some version of that same concrete house and barely-paved dirt road. the monotony and loneliness of arriving somewhere new, unanchored. trying to put down roots in a place when you’re not sure it wants you. the sacrifices and choices we make so that someday we end up with a house on american soil. when does that stop being the dream? when did it stop for pin jui? it’s pin jui sitting with a cup of tea in his dining room, alone in a big house. it’s angela with a half-eaten meal, wishing her father would say something. it’s the two of them together, framed side-by-side by a concrete block at the end. this film was alan yang’s way of producing a careful study of his own father, vivid in color and pensive in thought. it makes you want to stop and study your parents too; think about where they came from and what they have to say too.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">put your records on</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-03/put-your-records-on" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="put your records on" /><published>2020-03-29T18:54:55-04:00</published><updated>2020-03-29T18:54:55-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-03/put%20your%20records%20on</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-03/put-your-records-on">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;moving portraits:&lt;/strong&gt; a series about how the online and offline interact and collide&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Living memory, as told through live performances.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Live performance is a dialogue. It is a magical, unspoken conversation that connects the performer with each member of that audience. It is the connection that stays with you in physical space, forged through the visual, auditory, and tactile sensory input that is only possible by experiencing the performance/demonstration in a real, live setting. The relevance of live performance is to build that connection between observer and art, but also to initiate the live dialogue that occurs after. There is something special at the conclusion of a performance when you have a chance to react, process what you have seen, and reflect with those around you about what you have just experienced. Those conversations often cement the value and significance of the performance; and that reflection transforms a live performance into an experience and a memory that is enriching, immersive, and above all, timeless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology has an important place in preserving the magic of performances. Innovations such as asynchronous streaming and high-fidelity video encoding have made important contributions to preserving performances that would otherwise be lost to time, and also increasing accessibility of performances to those without the privilege or opportunity to see for themselves. Technology is a valuable knowledge-building and knowledge-sharing platform for performance, but it is not a substitute for the experience by itself. Recordings of live performances are akin to appetizers: they pique initial cultural and artistic interest, but are no replacement for the main course. They also play a role in introducing individuals to a diversity of styles and tastes in a low-cost, low-commitment manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Live performances, push you out of your comfort zone and force you to engage, intimately and directly. Live performance is probably one of the most intimate things you can do in a crowd of strangers. Some of the most beautiful live performances I have ever witnessed are largely decoupled from my own interests and talents, but they have been nevertheless enriching and have stayed with me ever since. Performances have shaped my life in important and intangible ways: the single most beautiful performance I have ever seen was Swan Lake at the MET Opera House in New York; memories of going to concerts and live plays with close friends; or even live performances I have attended locally and recognizing the breadth and diversity of talent around me. In a time where we are shuttering arthouses and cinemas and closing the doors to culture, we must think of how we are also losing our capacity to &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; in the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is vital to keep creating, to keep experiencing, and to keep sharing with others.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">moving portraits: a series about how the online and offline interact and collide Living memory, as told through live performances. Live performance is a dialogue. It is a magical, unspoken conversation that connects the performer with each member of that audience. It is the connection that stays with you in physical space, forged through the visual, auditory, and tactile sensory input that is only possible by experiencing the performance/demonstration in a real, live setting. The relevance of live performance is to build that connection between observer and art, but also to initiate the live dialogue that occurs after. There is something special at the conclusion of a performance when you have a chance to react, process what you have seen, and reflect with those around you about what you have just experienced. Those conversations often cement the value and significance of the performance; and that reflection transforms a live performance into an experience and a memory that is enriching, immersive, and above all, timeless.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">every time i describe a city, i am saying something about (new york)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-03/these-streets-will-make-you-feel-brand-new" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="every time i describe a city, i am saying something about (new york)" /><published>2020-03-23T19:20:24-04:00</published><updated>2020-03-23T19:20:24-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-03/these%20streets%20will%20make%20you%20feel%20brand%20new</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-03/these-streets-will-make-you-feel-brand-new">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bright lights / big city:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;a love letter to cityscapes and the urban form&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is nothing static about New York City; it is a constant ebb and flow of shifting gears and moving parts. I have observed the city as it lives and breathes as its own organism. Cities are dynamic, kinetic, and ever-changing: they bleed people and passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My heart is in New York City. I have seen my neighborhood grow older and mature as small businesses shutter close and undergo dramatic cosmetic changes to become tall residential buildings. I have watched rusty old payphone booths on street corners become supplanted by silver-polished internet hubs, beacons of technology that create an interconnected network of people and devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, cities were the products of geographic or economic circumstance. Now, cities are a conversation that adapt to the adapt to changing times and developing needs; we watch cities as they live and breathe as their own organisms. Technology, transportation, and infrastructure must meet the needs and demands of an ever-changing city climate. As cities spread out, our resources spread thin. Progress starts with sharing internally within communities and externally with other cities as the world globalizes at varying rates. After that, I think of the future of smart cities and how technology can be used to power and connect cities that also involve significant tradeoffs with citizen privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future of cities is still an open question: concerns about scaling sustainability, the burden of affordability and accessibility, and the sometimes scary. sensory-overload implications of building a “smart” city. It is a delicate balance and nobody has quite figured it out yet. Incubators like Alphabet’s Sidewalk Labs or the New York-based Intersection are envisioning the future of urban innovation that we must invest in and listen to. Cities are for people and the people must mobilize and respond in turn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2015, WIRED magazine published a feature titled “Eight Cities That Show You What the Future Will Look Like.” The feature named places from Los Angeles to Shanghai to Nairobi with smart design decisions that best exemplified cities of tomorrow. Once upon a time, &lt;em&gt;cities used to grow by accident&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the design of future cities are the exact opposite. There are no accidents here, only an infinite number of choices and dependencies and opportunity for the new urban form to take root.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A city shouldn’t just happen anymore. Every block, every building, every brick represents innumerable decisions. Decide well, and cities are magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">bright lights / big city: a love letter to cityscapes and the urban form There is nothing static about New York City; it is a constant ebb and flow of shifting gears and moving parts. I have observed the city as it lives and breathes as its own organism. Cities are dynamic, kinetic, and ever-changing: they bleed people and passion.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">with cities, it is as with dreams</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-03/invisible-cities" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="with cities, it is as with dreams" /><published>2020-03-22T19:05:44-04:00</published><updated>2020-03-22T19:05:44-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-03/invisible%20cities</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-03/invisible-cities">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bright lights / big city:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;a love letter to cityscapes and the urban form&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Invisible Cities&lt;/em&gt; by Italo Calvino is a literary monument to cities. &lt;em&gt;Invisible Cities&lt;/em&gt; was the last piece of literature I read in English class before graduating from high school. Calvino’s vivid love letter to cities in all their iterations captured the goodbye I said to my hometown city of New York as I left for a new city—Cambridge. My love for Calvino’s work is rooted in its sentimentality, but also originates in its effortless universality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite of the invisible cities is Chloe:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In Chloe, a great city, the people who move through the streets are all strangers. At each encounter, they imagine a thousand things about one another; meetings which could take place between them, conversations, surprises, caresses, bites. But no one greets anyone; eyes lock for a second, then dart away, seeking other eyes, never stopping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a quality that is unmistakably New York simmering underneath Calvino’s description: for that, it is truly beautiful. The greatest strength of &lt;em&gt;Invisible Cities&lt;/em&gt; is its intersectionality. One city could just as easily be another city. Just as the cities are themselves, Calvino’s descriptions are eternal and fluid.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">bright lights / big city: a love letter to cityscapes and the urban form Invisible Cities by Italo Calvino is a literary monument to cities. Invisible Cities was the last piece of literature I read in English class before graduating from high school. Calvino’s vivid love letter to cities in all their iterations captured the goodbye I said to my hometown city of New York as I left for a new city—Cambridge. My love for Calvino’s work is rooted in its sentimentality, but also originates in its effortless universality. My favorite of the invisible cities is Chloe: In Chloe, a great city, the people who move through the streets are all strangers. At each encounter, they imagine a thousand things about one another; meetings which could take place between them, conversations, surprises, caresses, bites. But no one greets anyone; eyes lock for a second, then dart away, seeking other eyes, never stopping. There is a quality that is unmistakably New York simmering underneath Calvino’s description: for that, it is truly beautiful. The greatest strength of Invisible Cities is its intersectionality. One city could just as easily be another city. Just as the cities are themselves, Calvino’s descriptions are eternal and fluid.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ii of iv | spring</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-02/spring" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ii of iv | spring" /><published>2020-02-29T19:35:13-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-29T19:35:13-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-02/spring</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-02/spring">&lt;p&gt;Though we may be grieving for the past few february weeks spent writing in the desolate winter, the 29th is a special leap day that comes with the promise of a new spring. For one day every four years, we stand in abeyance until we see the spring sun rise in the blue sky once again. We find our temporary respite in a dream of spring, a safe harbor among the turbulent seas of the winter nightmare.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Though we may be grieving for the past few february weeks spent writing in the desolate winter, the 29th is a special leap day that comes with the promise of a new spring. For one day every four years, we stand in abeyance until we see the spring sun rise in the blue sky once again. We find our temporary respite in a dream of spring, a safe harbor among the turbulent seas of the winter nightmare.</summary></entry></feed>