<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-26T23:28:40-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">recollectives</title><subtitle>a blog by kelly luo</subtitle><entry><title type="html">collections — no.006</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021-04/collections-006" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="collections — no.006" /><published>2021-04-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-04-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021-04/collections-006</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021-04/collections-006">&lt;h6 id=&quot;collections-a-weekly-reset&quot;&gt;collections: a weekly reset&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve decided to reorient my habits. All it takes is one day to compound to the next, or whatever the useless conventional wisdom says about this. With renewed purpose and a small dash of optimism, I’m back to talking out loud here. To get back in the groove of things, these are some catch-up musings from March.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fighting fire with fire&lt;/strong&gt;: the little fires everywhere in our pandemic year&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;faring well with spiritfarer:&lt;/strong&gt; get in spirits, we’re playing a cozy management game about dying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;💌&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fighting-fire-with-fire&quot;&gt;fighting fire with fire&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;the-little-fires-everywhere-in-our-pandemic-year&quot;&gt;the little fires everywhere in our pandemic year&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep writing about my grief like that will finally help me accept it. I found myself so burned and untetheredfor so much of the past two months. Found myself feeling like so much unlike myself. I kept rationalizing it as the one year anniversary of time as we knew it, but because I never profoundly dealt with it (in the way you deal with things where you crack, then fracture, then splinter open entirely) it felt like I was doing my very best to suppress the storm at bay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was like that for a long time, and I found myself overworked and muted and pouring all my time and energy into something I thought would make me feel better, or at least refocus my eternal restlessness. It turns out if you set time aside for yourself, you can actually focus on things you want to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to let myself burn for a while first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This entry is an excerpt from an email I wrote (mostly to and for myself):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched &lt;em&gt;little fires everywhere&lt;/em&gt; earlier in March as a life distraction, and I was really compelled by the imagery of the little fires we light in our own lives: the small, subtle, scattered flare-ups that become a wildfire when we distract ourselves or diminish the severity. How, like the management of real forest fires, sometimes we need to let those smaller fires burn so we don’t set everything ablaze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent the past year grieving and writing to rationalize the source of my grief (like what I’m doing here, you see) and somewhere along the way i got really tired of it. Because explaining to yourself that what you’re really feeling is sad and that it’s okay to feel sad and everybody else is feeling another version of sad doesn’t make you any less sad—and I’ve read so many versions of other people saying the same thing in different ways. So I keep going back to this factoid I once read about how humans weren’t meant to grieve in isolation and we are hard-wired to share the grief of a community together, but our circumstances have made that physically impossible. Instead, we mourn alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep recommending &lt;a href=&quot;https://annehelen.substack.com/p/no-im-not-ready&quot;&gt;no i’m not ready&lt;/a&gt; because no, i’m not ready. It’s centered around this one line about grief and metastasis: the splitting one oneself from the origin point to everywhere else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You convince yourself you’re ready to rejoin the world, you’re doing pretty okay, and then, days, weeks, months, even years down the line, something breaks inside you. Grief metastasizes when neglected. I have experienced it in the form of full body-wracking sobs when a song comes on the radio, and in dreams I wake up from with tears streaming down my face — but also in shitty behavior towards boyfriends and friends, in steaming, misdirected anger, in embarrassment and jealousy and shame. Processing loss entails acknowledging so much more than sadness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and how we might not be okay after; we may never be. because once the fire goes out, there is still ash and smoke—and nothing looks like same as it did before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;faring-well-with-spiritfarer&quot;&gt;faring well with spiritfarer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;get-in-spirits-were-playing-a-cozy-management-game-about-dying&quot;&gt;get in spirits, we’re playing a cozy management game about dying&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spiritfarer&lt;/em&gt; is a cozy management game about dying. That’s the buyline scattered across Steam and gaming consoles, a glowing endorsement of this aesthetic game with cutsey mechanics and morose undertone. The kind of adorable melancholia, personified in the starburst of a single-player game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent much of March (starting Saturday, March 13) immersed on this giant ship, navigating the afterworld with a bandwagon of rag-a-tag spirits who needed to pass on with a little help. If I had to psychoanalyzed why I started this game at this particular date and time in my life, it would look a little like a one-year anniversary where I needed to feel something again. Feeling, failing, fleeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conceit of this game is that nothing is particularly difficult, but you have to manage everything. It’s much like life in that sense, when smoothed out and satiated in the afterlife. There are certain mechanics of the game that I really love that put the cozy in management. Inherently, this is a game about collecting resources and crafting and farming: raw materials need to be crafted into something else to fulfill a higher purpose in the game. It’s soothing to know that there is no such thing as scarcity in the game: all the resources are abundant if you put in the time and effort to collect them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a game that mostly takes place on a ship on the infinite sea, save for the fantastical islands that are destinations for exploration, . The map is a projector and uses a starry navigator, the &lt;em&gt;everlight&lt;/em&gt;, the mark the start and end points of a journey. Grade school geometry insisted that a proper line segment is line segment is a part of a line that is bounded by two distinct end points, and every part of this endless journey is the composite of all these little segments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other parts of the game too: the characters to meet and collect onboard; the quests that give purpose to the long days of travel; the fishing and crafting to pass the longer nights; the in-game currency, glims, amassed for the exchange of ingredients, seeds, and materials; and the little minigames that repeat with a comforting repetition. It’s all part of the grind to progress and accumulate more (some meta-analysis for thought: you cannot escape capitalist impulses, even in death). The monotony of management that lets you relish in the coziness and consolation of moving forward in a game, in order to learn how to move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The soundtrack of this game is so perfectly instrumented. It made me feel calm, quiet, happy, and then despairing when I  needed to. The synesthetic mapping of these fictional locations on a map to melodic chords is divine: if you close your eyes, you feel that transformational sense of place envelop you. You are perched on the ship hull, sailing the high seas; the current of the ocean rushing beneath you, the starry expanse of the sky stretched above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warmly inviting you in, eager for you to continue on this journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-past-week&quot;&gt;this past week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;watched&lt;/strong&gt;: the 93rd academy awards&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;read&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;goodbye, again&lt;/em&gt; by jonny sun&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;listened&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GLO_57IV6Zc&quot;&gt;the story of “a thousand miles” by vanessa carlton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">collections: a weekly reset I’ve decided to reorient my habits. All it takes is one day to compound to the next, or whatever the useless conventional wisdom says about this. With renewed purpose and a small dash of optimism, I’m back to talking out loud here. To get back in the groove of things, these are some catch-up musings from March. fighting fire with fire: the little fires everywhere in our pandemic year faring well with spiritfarer: get in spirits, we’re playing a cozy management game about dying 💌</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">collections — no. 005</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021-04/collections-005" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="collections — no. 005" /><published>2021-04-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-04-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021-04/collections-005</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021-04/collections-005">&lt;h6 id=&quot;collections-a-weekly-accidentally-turned-monthly-reset&quot;&gt;collections: a weekly (accidentally turned monthly) reset&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am well over a month late with these words. I’ve been writing quite a bit for work, and those words have drained out of me onto Google Docs, but not quite on this little blog of mine. Perhaps the larger lesson here is that my words don’t have to be perfect; I just need to find the will in me to write them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;color me imperfect&lt;/strong&gt;: the renaissance of quarantined hobbies includes learning how to paint with messy, layered watercolors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the problem with pandemic storytelling&lt;/strong&gt;: let’s agree to stop romanticizing the times we are collectively trying to forget&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;meaning well with hypocrisy&lt;/strong&gt;: i can’t tell you how bad i am at something that i can’t take my own advice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;💌&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;color-me-imperfect&quot;&gt;color me imperfect&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;the-renaissance-of-quarantine-hobbies-includes-learning-how-to-paint-with-messy-layered-watercolors&quot;&gt;the renaissance of quarantine hobbies includes learning how to paint with messy, layered watercolors&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I decided I want to learn how to paint with watercolor. Given my historically established lack of artistic talent, I begin with overwhelmingly low expectations. However, I’m keen to learn and create some pieces that I might one day be proud of displaying somewhere in the open. Unvarnished, and susceptible to criticism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For rigor, I want to be clear about how different this is from my normal expected behavior. Throughout the course of my life, I have been repeatedly reminded of how poor of an artist I am. This has been a constant hum throughout my adolescence. There is visual evidence of how this is more fact than exaggeration. There is something about the perception to brain to hand-movement that doesn’t quite connect. I am a perfectionist, and the loose figures and shadows and edges that my hand produces on paper has never quite measured up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drawing may require some modicum of established talent, but my post-grad self believes that anything is a skill that can be learned. So with infinite free time in my hobby-less young adulthood, I have taken upon less productive hobbies that still produce creative value and little to no academic progression. Everything else can wait, I suppose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I admire how the colors bleed into each other: uncontrolled, chaotic. There is no stopping water that runs on paper, the imprint of dissolved pigment that binds to the page beneath. That the brush controls the strokes you make and the density of pigment and wash of color on textured paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I admire how terrible I am at it to start. The colors bleed into murky blobs of water and run all over. Watercolor is about deliberately coloring outside of the lines and letting the layers combine and collapse over each other. The deliberation in I follow YouTube tutorials destined for fifteen, twenty-minutes max that take me well over an hour. Scrub the timeline back to rewind the parts I missed, wonder how two people could have started in the same place yet ended up at wildly different midpoints (mine being the inferior version, of course).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to watercolor painting is patience. Layers need to dry before more paint is applied, or else the paper will saturate and curl up. The painting has its limits too; knowing when to push and when to hold back is half the battle during a painting session. Rush, and everything is ruined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, there’s the feeling I can’t shake when I finally finish something. Some vignette of an abstract scene of bleeding water-flush colors stained upon paper. Something like looks like something real. Not perfect, entirely copied, yet nevertheless an artifact of genuine effort and concentration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it feels good to be terrible at something. Maybe it feels good to put in that hour or two every weekend, knowing that I’ll produce something small that I might like, or something small I can tolerate at the very least. Maybe it feels good to do it over and over, and invest in nurturing this in the same way you invest in the things you like, buying supplies and bookmarking references and blocking sacred time to work on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe someday I’ll feel good and be good at it too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-problem-with-pandemic-storytelling&quot;&gt;the problem with pandemic storytelling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;lets-agree-to-stop-romanticizing-the-times-we-are-collectively-trying-to-forget&quot;&gt;let’s agree to stop romanticizing the times we are collectively trying to forget&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder if there are any good ways to capture the intricacies of the moment as it happens—without also then capitalizing on this innate impulse to record and fictionalize it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, there is a lot of story to tell here on the “the effects of quarantine and social isolation” and “how technology helped us stay connected” and “the power of the human spirit.” and these are valuable, worthy themes, and heady questions about the state of the human condition during these very strange times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it feels like we can tell those stories without “cheapening” it as entertainment made for distraction. We don’t need zoom meet-cute romcoms on reject network TV a la Freeform, nor did we ever ask for an Anne Hathaway and Chiwetel Ejiofor bank heist movie (we really, really didn’t. i promise you, HBO Max).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These lopsided fictionalizations do a disservice to the supposed “moment in time” they are honoring. It implies the moment is over, and we can move on and make fun of it and tell fictionalized stories about how maybe it wasn’t that bad under thinly-veiled humor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This should not become a new genre. Executives should not be greenlighting scripts because the pandemic feels like &lt;em&gt;topical&lt;/em&gt; storytelling. It’s not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;meaning-well-with-hypocrisy&quot;&gt;meaning well with hypocrisy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;i-cant-tell-you-how-bad-i-am-at-something-that-i-cant-take-my-own-advice&quot;&gt;i can’t tell you how bad i am at something that i can’t take my own advice&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a tumultuous relationship with the word hypocrite and the implication of hypocrisy. We ought to recognize hypocrisy everywhere. We’re all hypocrites; it’s what makes us human. Even AI is hypocritical. We are so hypocritical that we can’t even program our black box machines to be better than us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is something I say to people who know me relatively well, and I say it so casually and off-handedly that it’s probably a plea to myself to snap out of the delusion that it’s okay: “&lt;em&gt;I give good advice but I never take it&lt;/em&gt;.” It means that I will happily and freely dole out unsolicited advice about the best way for you to live your life, and turn around and do the exact opposite. I will advise you to care for yourself, to take that extra breather, to feel your feelings, to be pragmatic about the situation at hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I were in the same shoes, I would act on my own advice. If I were really honest, I’d talk about how I’m pretty mediocre about being kind and caring toward myself, how I never give my space for the breather, how I ignore my feelings because it’s easier to deal with them later, and how I don’t really find room for pragmatism in emotional situations because I would have averted course much earlier. There’s a lot there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m thinking about this because of this quote from a newsletter on work culture in remote work times (“&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://annehelen.substack.com/p/against-feel-free-to-take-some-time&quot;&gt;feel free to take time if you need it,&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;” they say. like i’ve probably said before. and yet, nobody has taken it):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I cannot tell you how deeply I believe that, how fiercely I want to dismantle this ethos of constant productivity and worksim, and how spectacularly bad I am at consistently taking my own advice. I am trying and failing and getting slightly better and backsliding. I have tried to be consistently transparent about that — because that is what unlearning an ideology looks like. It doesn’t mean that the work is bullshit. It means the work is hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How is anyone supposed to know what they need? Truth be told, we can’t even trust ourselves to know when to ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-past-week&quot;&gt;this past week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;watched&lt;/strong&gt;: falcon &amp;amp; the winter soldier (ep 05)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;read&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/books/under-review/why-we-mourn-girlhood&quot;&gt;why we mourn girlhood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;listened&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/0tQ9vBYpldCuikPsbgOVKA?si=e39f42d181dc4ff2&quot;&gt;untouchable (taylor’s version)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">collections: a weekly (accidentally turned monthly) reset I am well over a month late with these words. I’ve been writing quite a bit for work, and those words have drained out of me onto Google Docs, but not quite on this little blog of mine. Perhaps the larger lesson here is that my words don’t have to be perfect; I just need to find the will in me to write them. color me imperfect: the renaissance of quarantined hobbies includes learning how to paint with messy, layered watercolors the problem with pandemic storytelling: let’s agree to stop romanticizing the times we are collectively trying to forget meaning well with hypocrisy: i can’t tell you how bad i am at something that i can’t take my own advice 💌</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">collections — no. 004</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021-03/collections-004" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="collections — no. 004" /><published>2021-03-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-03-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021-03/collections-004</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021-03/collections-004">&lt;h6 id=&quot;collections-a-weekly-reset&quot;&gt;collections: a weekly reset&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s March 18th. My writing gets further and further away from consistency. It’s been a hard few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;my life into folklore:&lt;/strong&gt; the grammy awards, and this album that snapped me out of a quarantine stupor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;post-apocalyptic musicscapes&lt;/strong&gt;: music tells time better than our memories can&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;you can’t say someone deserved better&lt;/strong&gt;: nobody should deserve justice if we all entitled to it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;💌&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-life-into-folklore&quot;&gt;my life into folklore&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;the-grammy-awards-and-this-album-that-snapped-me-out-of-a-quarantine-stupor&quot;&gt;the grammy awards, and this album that snapped me out of a quarantine stupor&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had called it an interminable summer. The days were senseless and the months were beyond my senses. I couldn’t feel the time passing, only a current of afternoons and nights that eclipsed one after the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among critic circles, &lt;em&gt;folklore&lt;/em&gt; was lionized as the “quintessential quarantine album”. It was a concept borne and executed only under circumstances as cosmic and devastating as the past year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the kind of thing none of us expected, but once it was part of our lives, it made itself permanent. &lt;em&gt;Folklore&lt;/em&gt; won a &lt;em&gt;Grammy&lt;/em&gt; for that, Taylor’s third &lt;em&gt;Grammy Award&lt;/em&gt; in fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;post-apocalyptic-musicscapes&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;post-apocalyptic musicscapes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;music-tells-time-better-than-our-memories-can&quot;&gt;music tells time better than our memories can&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My sonic memories of 2017, in soft vocals and sparse instruments. It sounds, overwhelmingly, like &lt;em&gt;Novo Amor&lt;/em&gt;. How the timbre of his music transports me to long bus rides in the January cold. Back in 2017 when everything was just beginning and would be over as soon as I knew it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;you-cant-say-someone-deserved-better&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;you can’t say someone deserved better&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;nobody-should-deserve-justice-if-we-all-entitled-to-it&quot;&gt;nobody should deserve justice if we all entitled to it&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news has been treacherous this week (and the week before). The headlines have been marred by violence and suffering and outrage. It’s all so inevitable, yet inevitably pitiful. The news cycle won’t stop, but time is supposed to go on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-past-week&quot;&gt;this past week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;watched&lt;/strong&gt;: raya and the last dragon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;read&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://griefbacon.substack.com/p/thomas-cromwell-is-real-and-strong&quot;&gt;thomas cromwell is real and strong and my friend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;listened&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Uzii44SDYFA&quot;&gt;cardigan / august / willow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">collections: a weekly reset It’s March 18th. My writing gets further and further away from consistency. It’s been a hard few weeks. my life into folklore: the grammy awards, and this album that snapped me out of a quarantine stupor post-apocalyptic musicscapes: music tells time better than our memories can you can’t say someone deserved better: nobody should deserve justice if we all entitled to it 💌</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">collections — no. 003</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021-03/collections-003" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="collections — no. 003" /><published>2021-03-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-03-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021-03/collections-003</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021-03/collections-003">&lt;h6 id=&quot;collections-a-weekly-reset&quot;&gt;collections: a weekly reset&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s March 5th. I publish each edition later, and later. I might never catch up to a regular schedule. A little is always more than nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;human exhaust&lt;/strong&gt;: it’s not zoom fatigue, but it’s not like talking to people is getting any easier.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kick it up a notch:&lt;/strong&gt; the ugly duckling of smartphones, the display notch, has blossomed into a ubiquitous design pattern.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;💌&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;human-exhaust&quot;&gt;human exhaust&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;its-not-zoom-fatigue-but-its-not-like-talking-to-people-is-getting-any-easier&quot;&gt;it’s not zoom fatigue, but it’s not like talking to people is getting any easier&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know what running on fumes feels like. I’ve felt it so many times in my life; that constant falling apart and needing to put myself back together every morning. Humpty dumpty and the sisyphean struggle.. Eyes bloodshot, muscles weary. It feels terrible. This is not it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is nothing like it. This is a year of prolonged, silent suffering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m tired of talking to people but I need to talk to people at the same time. That never-ending uphill battle of jumping from video call to video call because my entire existence has been tethered to moving faces in a resizeable browser window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m tired of you, and thinking about you too. I’m not exhausted, but I feel wasted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;kick-it-up-a-notch&quot;&gt;kick it up a notch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;the-ugly-duckling-of-smartphones-the-display-notch-has-blossomed-into-a-ubiquitous-design-pattern&quot;&gt;the ugly duckling of smartphones, the display notch, has blossomed into a ubiquitous design pattern.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many, many years ago (closer to three years ago), the media went crazy over the unveiling of a sleek new iPhone model that courageously rendered the home button ancient history, and replaced it with an edge-to-edge display. Full display save for a singular black notch at the top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were a laughing stock for quite a while in the press until the tides turned and everybody bought the newest iPhone. Then they bought the next one. Then their competitors also began artificially integrating notches on their display, because somehow that became the newest digital normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, any representation of a smartphone features a notch. The notch has become symbolic of a premium, luxurious, and high-quality screen experience. The narrative shifted in their favor. We don’t know why, but it did, and all of a sudden Apple owned the notch. Nobody is laughing now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-past-week&quot;&gt;this past week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;watched&lt;/strong&gt;: nomadland (dir. chloe zhao)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;read&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecut.com/2021/03/mary-kate-ashley-olsen-the-row.html&quot;&gt;beige ambition (the cut)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;listened&lt;/strong&gt;: “&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/5LID7Ihnsvi7vpbCWL4xQF?si=jNmSLQqMSRGIXoM0dPbNVw&quot;&gt;celadon &amp;amp; gold&lt;/a&gt;” by maggie rogers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">collections: a weekly reset It’s March 5th. I publish each edition later, and later. I might never catch up to a regular schedule. A little is always more than nothing. human exhaust: it’s not zoom fatigue, but it’s not like talking to people is getting any easier. kick it up a notch: the ugly duckling of smartphones, the display notch, has blossomed into a ubiquitous design pattern. 💌</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">collections — no. 002</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021-02/collections-002" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="collections — no. 002" /><published>2021-02-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-02-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021-02/collections-002</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021-02/collections-002">&lt;h6 id=&quot;collections-a-weekly-reset&quot;&gt;collections: a weekly reset&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s February 23rd. I’m trying my best to write with some semblance of consistency, and forcing myself to write, even if I secretly don’t want to, for at least an hour a week. Consistent quantity creates quality, said a self-help book (probably).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;martin scorsese hates content&lt;/strong&gt;: one of the godfathers of modern cinema has strong words about what the algorithm did to content&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wandavision made (linear) television cool again:&lt;/strong&gt; if netflix invented the binge, then disney+ reinvented water cooler talk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;💌&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;martin-scorsese-hates-content&quot;&gt;martin scorsese hates content&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;one-of-the-godfathers-of-modern-cinema-has-strong-words-about-what-the-algorithm-did-to-content&quot;&gt;one of the godfathers of modern cinema has strong words about what the algorithm did to content&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The twitter-sphere was in an uproar because one of the most renowned and decorated filmmakers of our time was criticizing the art of the Netflix binge and the cinematic universe of comic books. Content is a dirty word, likened to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://harpers.org/archive/2021/03/il-maestro-federico-fellini-martin-scorsese/&quot;&gt;systemic devaluation and reduction of the art of cinema&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Content” became a business term for all moving images: a David Lean movie, a cat video, a Super Bowl commercial, a superhero sequel, a series episode. It was linked, of course, not to the theatrical experience but to home viewing, on the streaming platforms that have come to overtake the moviegoing experience, just as Amazon overtook physical stores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love content. If I could say content consumption (and then thinking about it) was a hobby, I would turn it into a self-proclaimed profession. I love consuming content, and I am hoping to do it consciously by thinking out loud and morphing those thoughts into these words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There flaws are numerous; I’ll name a few. First is the historically exclusionary vantage point from which he is writing. The title of tastemaker is often reserved for the select few who manifest the wealth and cultural capital to decide what constitutes culture (and who gets to make more of it). Curators are a mere cultivation of the elite, in granting a handful with the influence to make opinionated decisions about what the rest of us are allowed to like and spend our money on. The concentration of the custodianship on those with existing connections and clout. They were born with the high ground of high culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had a hill to die on, it would be the valley between high culture and low culture.  The auteurs want us to be patrons, not consumers. Content is commodification, and their art is anything but.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a shame it would be to make good art accessible; shame on those who enjoy anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wandavision-made-linear-television-cool-again&quot;&gt;wandavision made (linear) television cool again&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;if-netflix-invented-the-binge-then-disney-reinvented-water-cooler-talk&quot;&gt;if netflix invented the binge, then disney+ reinvented water cooler talk&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the surprise of absolutely nobody, I love television. It’s the only part of my personality that I have left. Wandavision is nerdy: nerdy in the sense that it is based off of comic books (and comic book characters turned into blockbuster movies), but it also nerds out on television. The conceit of Wandavision is that Wanda has create a television-esque fantasy world for her life with Vision. Each episode is based on a hyper-specific sitcom era, from &lt;em&gt;Bewitched&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;Modern Family&lt;/em&gt;, but they’re not parodies—they’re homages. They are delicate recreations that honor the source inspiration rather than make a mockery of it. That is explicitly how it avoids feeling anachronistic or disjointed: these era-spanning episodes simply inhabit the era they are in. It admires the good old television tropes as much as it transforms them and riffs on them for a modern audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as Scorsese’s critique goes for media and the algorithm, his homeland is the art of cinema. Mine is television and the telegenicity of stories that become rendered into digestible, thirty-minute to an hour pockets of weekly narrative. Netflix gets a lot of credit where it is due for pioneering the “binge” habit loop, and it’s marketing department prides itself on the innovation. After Netflix began dumping entire series of shows with all the episodes at once, it introduced “binge-worthiness” and a metric of worth for television. In a wild game of endurance, the more episodes you could continuously consume in a single sitting, the more prized the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This distribution and consumption model destroyed the traditional conventions of linear tv: the idea that a season of a show would run its course over a non-instantaneous span of time, the episodes would air week after week. After the episode aired, you would have to wait until next week for the next one. As Netflix grew into a content powerhouse, audiences began expecting episodes to drop all at once: they had been spoiled, and grown accustomed to the instant gratification. The water cooler conversation about the last episode (and you can’t spoil what hasn’t aired)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wandavision is not that kind of show. It’s a slow-burn. It has layers of mystery and suspense that only work because the episodes are spaced out, and each episode ends on a cliffhanger that require a week of theorizing and fan speculation. That is what makes tv feel special over a prolonged period of time: the way the conversation stretches into weeks and months, and viewers are just as excited as they were during week one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come on Wandavision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-past-week&quot;&gt;this past week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;watched&lt;/strong&gt;: wandavision episode 7 (all about agnes)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;read&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://readwildness.com/25/coval-mantra&quot;&gt;mantra for when it’s dark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;listened&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NbuI7p9cgLU&quot;&gt;i told the stars about you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">collections: a weekly reset It’s February 23rd. I’m trying my best to write with some semblance of consistency, and forcing myself to write, even if I secretly don’t want to, for at least an hour a week. Consistent quantity creates quality, said a self-help book (probably). martin scorsese hates content: one of the godfathers of modern cinema has strong words about what the algorithm did to content wandavision made (linear) television cool again: if netflix invented the binge, then disney+ reinvented water cooler talk 💌</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">i’m writing a newsletter, she said.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021-02/blog-turned-newsletter" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="i'm writing a newsletter, she said." /><published>2021-02-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-02-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021-02/blog%20turned%20newsletter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021-02/blog-turned-newsletter">&lt;p&gt;At the start of this year, I said &lt;em&gt;I wanted to write more&lt;/em&gt;. It was more of an aspiration than a resolution, but what’s aspiration without a little inspiration?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the plan: at the end of every week, I’ll block off thirty minutes to an hour on my calendar. I’ll write about what I thought about that week, spinning aberrant thoughts into a periodical narrative. Then, I’ll publish it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t a newsletter in the formal sense  (I’m not a newsletter writer, nor do I really want to be). It will be more like a semi-public diary. Some of these will be half-formed ideas that I have been nurturing; others will be half-compromises for fully-fleshed essays I hope to write one day but lack the energy and motivation to do so. I will get there one day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m always thinking about something, and I mean this in the way that I care and pay attention a lot of things and they have the luxury of taking up space in my brain. I’ll take any opportunity to pathologize my inner thoughts and reason through my neuroses. A lot of this will be captured through the lens of my relationship with technology and the internet. The kind of armchair sociocultural anthropologist that pays homage to her tools and instruments. Infusions of soft-hued nostalgia and cultural references.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">At the start of this year, I said I wanted to write more. It was more of an aspiration than a resolution, but what’s aspiration without a little inspiration? Here’s the plan: at the end of every week, I’ll block off thirty minutes to an hour on my calendar. I’ll write about what I thought about that week, spinning aberrant thoughts into a periodical narrative. Then, I’ll publish it. This isn’t a newsletter in the formal sense (I’m not a newsletter writer, nor do I really want to be). It will be more like a semi-public diary. Some of these will be half-formed ideas that I have been nurturing; others will be half-compromises for fully-fleshed essays I hope to write one day but lack the energy and motivation to do so. I will get there one day. I’m always thinking about something, and I mean this in the way that I care and pay attention a lot of things and they have the luxury of taking up space in my brain. I’ll take any opportunity to pathologize my inner thoughts and reason through my neuroses. A lot of this will be captured through the lens of my relationship with technology and the internet. The kind of armchair sociocultural anthropologist that pays homage to her tools and instruments. Infusions of soft-hued nostalgia and cultural references.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">collections — no. 001</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021-02/collections-001" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="collections — no. 001" /><published>2021-02-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-02-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021-02/collections-001</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021-02/collections-001">&lt;h6 id=&quot;collections-a-weekly-reset&quot;&gt;collections: a weekly reset&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s February 15th. We are one-and-a-half months into the new year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;all stories have a beginning, middle, and end&lt;/strong&gt;: to all the boys: always and forever ends as a love letter to endings and how hard it is to say goodbye.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;we were both young&lt;/strong&gt;: love story (taylor’s version) collapsed the years between middle school and adulthood.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;something like chasing stars&lt;/strong&gt;: the american narrative is obsessed with space movies and sending astronauts on interstellar adventures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;💌&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;all-stories-have-a-beginning-middle-and-end&quot;&gt;all stories have a beginning, middle, and end&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;to-all-the-boys-always-and-forever-ends-as-a-love-letter-to-endings-and-how-hard-it-is-to-say-goodbye&quot;&gt;to all the boys: always and forever ends as a love letter to endings and how hard it is to say goodbye.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think I fully understood myself as a person, as a young woman shedding the relics of her teenage girlhood, until I realized &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; I love &lt;em&gt;to all the boys&lt;/em&gt; so much. It’s something that transcends a lifelong appreciation for romcoms and aesthetic staples of the tried and true teen experience. It is deeply personal in a way I have spent so long trying to articulate. I am working on a draft of it, borne from the genetics of a movie review and personal essay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have watched the final &lt;em&gt;to all the boys&lt;/em&gt; installment a few times since it was released this past weekend and it leaves my half-empty rather than half-full. I had waited so long for this final film and it was finally here. As soon as it was here, it was over. There will be no more &lt;em&gt;to all the boys.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was struck by the sudden dread and fascination by the timeline: that I have spent the past two and a half years of my life waiting for this adaptation. That I had eager, but relatively low expectations when the first film came out as an adaptation of this cutesy YA series I had first read as a high school summer; and it had transcended my wildest pastel-pink daydreams for what this series could be. How I had spent the summer of 2018 re-reading the trilogy during my internship commute, and I found myself sympathizing with our teenage protagonist when I was decidedly no longer a teenager in her shoes. That span of time since has been spent waiting for this final release in earnest, of the best and most emotionally satisfying part of this series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It reminds me how precarious and delicate happiness can feel if it is measured by the yardstick of arbitrary milestones. How we will be inevitably be disappointed and confused when it doesn’t go according to plan. It’s not like there wasn’t a plan, and what good is a plan when it’s never put into place?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-were-both-young&quot;&gt;we were both young&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;love-story-taylors-version-collapses-the-years-between-middle-school-and-adulthood&quot;&gt;love story (taylor’s version) collapses the years between middle school and adulthood.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taylor Swift is re-recording her old albums. She is reclaiming ownership of her sophomore album, and every other album that is an artifact of her artistic genius, whimsy, and imagination. &lt;em&gt;Fearless&lt;/em&gt; is Taylor at her most wide-eyed and naïve, committed to storybook endings and fairytale romances before she had to grow up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;so before i say anything else, let me just say that it was a real honor to get to be a teenager alongside you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirteen years have elapsed, such that &lt;em&gt;Fearless&lt;/em&gt; is practically a teenager by this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listening to  “Love Story” again through more mature ears doesn’t make the song any less lovely and magical than the first time around. This was the song that catapulted Taylor into the stratosphere for the first time, and it was the kind of inescapable song about a forbidden Romeo and Juliet-esque romance that made any middle school girl recount her most fanciful romantic plots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much time has passed since the original that it’s updated iteration feels tinted through  Taylor’s memory and the parallel track of my nostalgia. It’s a weird feeling that will only compound when the full &lt;em&gt;Fearless&lt;/em&gt; album is released in April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;something-like-chasing-stars&quot;&gt;something like chasing stars&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;the-american-narrative-is-obsessed-with-space-movies-and-sending-astronauts-on-interstellar-adventures&quot;&gt;the american narrative is obsessed with space movies and sending astronauts on interstellar adventures&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Camelot era “Space Race” adapted by Hollywood blockbusters is gilded in American exceptionalism. Hollywood puts movies about the moon landing or Apollo missions into the remix machine in hopes of reclaiming a narrative about the best and brightest minds embarking on a perilous journey; some Uncle Sam-spiked cocktail of reckless bravery, blind optimism, and pure patriotism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the most part, sci-fi gets a bad reputation unless it involves astronauts. There are no government agencies and institutions with the name-recognition and prestige as NASA and JPL. We all think space is cool. The idea of making to far-distant lands and seeing beyond the galaxy is a fantasy we have entertained in real-life and in the movies. It is a self-aggrandizement of the human condition that we were always destined for more than the Earth we call(ed) home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can name a bunch of space-esque movies in rapid succession, their plots similar and ambition limitless: Interstellar. Gravity. The Martian. Ad Astra. First Man. High Life. These one-or-two word titles are about a man who has been launched into space; a man vs. nature conflict where the man is an astronaut and the nature is the impenetrable mystery of outer space. Note: the male astronaut always seems to get first billing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until science catches up with fiction, we should expect to see more space movies hitting theaters. Each a riff on an old problem and new adventure, with familiar references to scientific concepts rendered down for an everyday palette. They are unified by this ominous doomsday plot that Earth is no longer untenable and the miracle of human grit and tenacity is the only thing preventing the apocalypse; rather than remedy the Earth, we seek &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt;. A test as old as time about the limits of humanity at the edges of the universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-past-week&quot;&gt;this past week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;watched&lt;/strong&gt;: to all the boys: always and forever&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;read&lt;/strong&gt;: the martian by andy weir&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;listened&lt;/strong&gt;: floodlines (the atlantic)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">collections: a weekly reset It’s February 15th. We are one-and-a-half months into the new year. all stories have a beginning, middle, and end: to all the boys: always and forever ends as a love letter to endings and how hard it is to say goodbye. we were both young: love story (taylor’s version) collapsed the years between middle school and adulthood. something like chasing stars: the american narrative is obsessed with space movies and sending astronauts on interstellar adventures 💌</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">i can’t sleep because i’m thinking about</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021-01/insomnia-thoughts" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="i can't sleep because i'm thinking about" /><published>2021-01-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-01-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021-01/insomnia-thoughts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021-01/insomnia-thoughts">&lt;p&gt;Sleepless nights when I try to make sense of the confused chaos of my own brain. These are the late hours when I think about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;why we can’t let teen girls like things and the &lt;em&gt;purchasing power&lt;/em&gt; they command once their wallets are valuable&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;skewed perception of fiscal value and monetary services, until one day we learn about &lt;em&gt;wall street&lt;/em&gt; and everything changes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the implicit generational trauma of being a &lt;em&gt;child of the internet&lt;/em&gt;, information overload and polarization unbound.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the fuzzy edges of my consciousness from self-aware to world-aware in a house of cards newscycle: that post 9-11, kindergarten during katrina, elementary school financial crisis &lt;em&gt;state of mind&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;🌃&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Sleepless nights when I try to make sense of the confused chaos of my own brain. These are the late hours when I think about: why we can’t let teen girls like things and the purchasing power they command once their wallets are valuable skewed perception of fiscal value and monetary services, until one day we learn about wall street and everything changes the implicit generational trauma of being a child of the internet, information overload and polarization unbound. the fuzzy edges of my consciousness from self-aware to world-aware in a house of cards newscycle: that post 9-11, kindergarten during katrina, elementary school financial crisis state of mind. 🌃</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">happy, free, confused, and lonely (in the best way)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020-12/how-old-are-we-really" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="happy, free, confused, and lonely (in the best way)" /><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020-12/how-old-are-we-really</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020-12/how-old-are-we-really">&lt;h6 id=&quot;on-turning-twenty-two-in-the-year-2020&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;on turning &lt;strong&gt;twenty-two&lt;/strong&gt; in the year 2020.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a certain rite of passage when you turn twenty-two. All the major young adult milestones are presumably behind you: you’ve voted in an election, had your first legal drink of alcohol, and graduated from university. Everything ahead of you now exists in the postgraduate limbo called the rest of your life. You also listen to Taylor Swift’s “22” because &lt;em&gt;i don’t know about you&lt;/em&gt;, but you wouldn’t really be twenty-two without it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A perfect storm of happy, free, confused, and lonely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take these last three minutes and twenty seven seconds with your hipster glasses and oversized t-shirts. You may never feel this way again, but&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 25px&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;everything will be alright if we just keep—&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“22” is a song that has turned an unremarkable age into a fanciful destination. Nothing is new anymore, but you’ll know the feeling of one of those sleepless nights–those nights you were surrounded by everyone and no one at the same time, where nothing felt like everything and everything you could have ever wanted was in one place, and it could have been a perfect polaroid to recall in your sentimentally senile days . When &lt;em&gt;Red&lt;/em&gt; debuted in 2012 with the masterpiece that is “22”, we were twelve going on thirteen: we had just found our first footholds in our teen years with this beacon of twenty-two to look up to. Some day we would know what it would feel like to dress, look, act carefree and unencumbered in the cosmic glow of our birthday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we get to that fateful day, the self-referential title serves its fullest purpose. “22” is about turning 22, embracing it, wondering what it’s all about. When we play it at the loudest volume our speakers can tolerate and shout the chorus at the top of our lungs, it’s the &lt;em&gt;hoping&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;wanting&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;celebrating&lt;/em&gt; the misery and magic of turning twenty-two in a cursed year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re a kid, you close your eyes and blow out your candles to count down the days until you become an adult. Twenty-one is supposed to be the last milestone of young adulthood. It’s the line in the sand that demarcates &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt;. A concrete moment in time that soon slips past, and the years become quicksand draining to the bottom of the hourglass. There are no more deadlines to meet, just darkness at the finish line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That treacherous darkness has crept up on us the same year we are turning twenty-two. The same year that was supposed to hold a college graduation, post-graduate travels, moving to a new city, starting a full-time job—now footnotes to an unfathomable tragedy of the commons. To come of age in truly the strangest of times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2020 has been a typhoon of magic and misery. An agent of chaos that tore through the bedrock of every institution we thought we knew. A year of nothing but bad news and steeply-sloped curves. We have all written and spoken about it at length, and there will never be enough words for it; and furthermore, any attempt to summarize these events in a year-end reflection would be disingenuous. The wounds are still raw and reeling and the nation has never stopped bleeding. We may never recover from the ghosts of living in this haunted madhouse, but the least we can do is shut them in the attic, go downstairs to the living room couch, and watch the sparkling ball drop on the cusp of 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in May, I wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.kellyluo.me/2020-05/all-of-a-sudden-i-miss-everyone&quot;&gt;i need to get my story straight&lt;/a&gt; to get my own story straight about graduating virtually and the whirlwind of moving out, saying goodbye, and closing a chapter on life. It was one of the hardest things I’ve ever tried to write and it felt so important to me in the moment. Throughout the seven months and multiple lifetimes since I finished it, I come back to it and reflect on how little has changed. How fractured my emotional state had been at the time when I wrote it, how I had been so desperate to write my way out of my own feelings, and how the Elmer’s glue didn’t hold up when I held up the mirror at the end of December.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of December, in the minutes and few hours before the glistening mirrorball descends upon an empty Times Square, I find myself searching for answers to everything I had been missing and looking for this past year. Waiting for the crystal ball to drop and ordain our futures for the next year, the tea leaves of what 2021 may have in store for me now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;happy&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;happy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no preamble here on the meaning of happiness and whether it exists or how to attain it. We are all some combination of too disillusioned, despondent, and delirious to debate on happiness. 2020 itself is the prognosis of a bad time; in future years, it will become an omen. When times are bad, we turn to things that we think will make us happy. That matters a lot: finding the small, simple joys in things and holding on whenever possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s about finding and creating joy when we can. There’s so little of it these days that we should be thoughtful and open about how we care for ourselves and for others. These days, it’s in the small things. Receiving a nice email in your inbox; seeing well-wishes in an unexpected text; and people who show up for you even when it’s hard. The devil is always in the details. Feeling seen and heard in the small, minute details shows you were paying attention, and that attention is what sustains us. Going out of our way to do those small acts of kindness is kindling: it might not make us any happier, but it will make us kinder. If we can spark a little joy, we will all be better for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent many quarantine months figuring out what made me happy, because whatever I had up until that point wasn’t quite doing it for me. I clung to empty rituals as a life raft, and when they didn’t work, I found myself spiraling. I had been so enamoured with practices and pretense that would confer feelings of self-described satisfaction or fulfillment. The proverbial glass isn’t half-empty or half-full when the looking glass is foggy to begin with. Not sure if we’re looking at our true selves, who we think we are, or the version we project upon others. I am starting to learn how to let go and not base my emotional state on the whims of the world. The world changes so quickly that the emotional whiplash is seldom worth it. Lately, I have been reevaluating the things that make me happy and how to find that elusive equanimity I have always been looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I found myself more empty than I was happy, I had this restless and disruptive energy that neutralized me in turn. It made me feel complacent and lethargic, a little more hopeless and resigned than my disposition normally called for. Resignation was how I felt for most of this past year. I am resolved to demand more of myself. I think I wanted to be angry at myself, but I’m not, nor should I be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A word from the unwise: you should never be angry with yourself; be gentle, be kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have some resolutions for the new year. I haven’t written them down yet, because writing them is the very first step to realizing them, but I will. Time will tell on where I go from here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free&quot;&gt;free&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freedom as an oxymoron in the year the word “quarantine” entered the public consciousness and embedded itself into our national lexicon. No conversation could end without at least one reference to quarantine activities or feelings because it was on all of our minds and there was no point in beating around the bush. Days and months and nearly a year spent indoors as time melded into a messy mirage of bread-baking and Netflix binges. The headlines were a stream of white noise in the background, the torrential roar of crisis upon disaster upon tragedy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year was also the first time I felt free, in the cognitive and not physical sense. After I graduated in my living room and the three-seconds of my photo on the tv were up, I watched sixteen years of schooling collapse with nothing to do and nowhere to go. I could do anything and everything (within the confines of my room and the wide-open internet); it seemed like I had infinite time to channel the restless, creative energy I had bottled up, much like releasing a genie from the bottle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I mostly did nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought a lot. I slept some nights, couldn’t sleep on others. I questioned, mulled over my thoughts and feelings and spent cycles spinning in circles. I read, but not as much as I would have liked. I caught up on all the YouTube videos, tv shows, and movies I never had enough time for and eagerly welcomed them as distractions. I went through phases of baking and crafting and every permutation of a productive hobby I could develop via an online tutorial. I did all those things and nothing much at all (see: &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.kellyluo.me/2020-12/2020-in-review&quot;&gt;2020, in review&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the first time I was finally unencumbered by the institutions upon which I had validated myself and sought success. I had the privilege of freedom to think and mostly do as I wanted, yet I couldn’t help but feel trapped at the same time. It didn’t make much sense, though I suspect that kind of cognitive dissonance isn’t intended to make sense. The world was once so big and seemingly imploded overnight inside the confined spaces where we waited out the storm. When the real world collapsed, the potential of the digital world rose from its chaos. There was so much I could do, and still so much work left to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lonely&quot;&gt;lonely&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been a lonely year. Lonely in the way where we’ve all been stuck inside of our homes during extended periods of self-quarantine—but also lonely in the way where you’re supposed to be starting the rest of your life yet you’re still sitting in your childhood bedroom and navigating each existential crisis beneath the soft glow of string lights. Lonely in the way where you’re constantly surrounded by others on video calls and text messages. Blink once, and it’s an empty room; blink twice, and it’s just you and your face illuminated by the blue glow of the screen. Lonely as much as it is isolating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; see people; but the sample size is limited and the variables are limitless. There is a guarded intimacy to a good, long video call. Physical space is bounded into rectangles side-by-side on a screen, morphed into the dreamscape backgrounds that hide our physical reality. Temporal bounds are demarcated by a timestamp that state how much time has passed since the call started, yet no time has passed at all. Intrinsic desire for social and emotional connection becomes whittled down to terse life updates, awkward icebreakers, and occasional group therapy sessions for the soul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the most amount time any of us have ever spent by ourselves, alone with our thoughts and fears and hopes and dreams. The way we scared ourselves as much as the world scared us. The world has always been scary, but the terror in 2020 is in how things have been and not how they should be. When we envision personal freedoms in this modern century, we cannot do so without dialogue on racial justice and environmental justice. This was a year, burned: watching historic systems of oppression and inequality exacerbate and flare, asking how we can continue to create and promote equity when the people are listening, but those who represent the people aren’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Left alone to our own devices, figuratively and literally, it was a year that made us lonely and lonesome. Grateful for the people we have, forever missing our closest circle of family and friends. Counting the people who mattered most and holding them close. Yet when everyone retreated home, we also missed everyone we didn’t know. The buzz of a city street from the nameless, faceless strangers who wouldn’t give you an extra second of their day. The casual acquaintances that added such rich texture to your life: the less-than-acquaintances you crossed paths with at the same time on your daily commute, the acquaintances-by-name you would politely say hello to and nothing more, the friendly-acquaintances you would bump into at odd locations and be enthralled at just how small the world is. The people who made your life feel a little more full and lively at the edges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;confused&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;confused&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2020 has been a black hole of memory and time warps, and we’ll stumble into 2021 in a confused and hazy spell. Things happened that I’ve since forgotten about, and then will recall at a later date, and all those dates will have converged to a single happening in a separate lifetime. Such as: in May, we all became obsessed with &lt;em&gt;Normal People&lt;/em&gt;. I, too, watched and read it, and then told my friends to do the same. Obama recommended in his year-end book list when 2019 was still on the cusp of becoming 2020, and Sally Rooney had been hailed as the literary voice of the millennial generation. The show became a critical darling in the late spring, when things were still bad but we thought there was a glimmer of hope for late summer. I really wish I could stop talking about this book and show, and maybe I can finally lay it to rest after this one final thought: there is a good reason we keep coming back to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had more or less followed in the footsteps of Connell and Marianne: starting from those awkward teen years through the exploratory college years and all the way to the amorphous postgraduate years. We do the same things they did and caution ourselves against the same mistakes. They cite authors and texts they once read in university seminars—the syllabi and body of references that gave them the authority to reflect on socioeconomic stratification and racial disparity and systemic inequity in their own bubbles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That might just be a function of being twenty-two, but the causality is bleak. The point of it is: I don’t think we want to know who we are. We self-diagnose and pick at our own scars until they start to bleed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up until twenty-two, I was foremost a student—and now I’m just me. I don’t really know who that is and there’s not enough space here to articulate that in a pithy elevator pitch. I have things I care about, things I think a lot about, things I value and keep coming back to. Then I ask myself if all of that is enough in this day and age, in this iteration, this confused imprint of a person that keeps wondering and waiting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the versions of myself before this year are largely volcanic ash now, preserved under the sediment of the months and years that have elapsed and exploded upon this year. The principles of my education forced me to learn and define who I was within those constructs, and now they no longer exist. There is so much to unlearn and unpack at the same time. I wonder who I am; and which parts of me I’ve sacrificed at the altar of my own expectations. There is a selfish ignorance to this train of thought, a hyper-awareness of the self and unawareness of the world. Assuredly, every other recent high-achieving college graduate feels the same way: the shell of themselves at seventeen metamorphized into relentless self-possession at twenty-one (going on twenty-two). In the apocalyptic aftermath, I am learning how to learn, and unlearn, again. Learning is lifelong, and we know how long things can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I celebrated many twenty-second birthdays over Zoom this year. An entire generation of twenty-two year olds forged on the dignified stage of video chat. We made endearingly embarrassing birthday powerpoints, blasted Taylor Swift as loud as our tinny computer speakers would allow, and reminisced about the last time we were all in the same physical room together (and I’ll think back to one of those perfect polaroid nights back in March and the lost time since). I was the last to turn twenty-two, and by the time it was my turn, I had already memorized the chorus at age twelve and ready to let Taylor usher me into the next ceremonial stage of life. As happy, free, confused, and lonely as I can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s where I am now. Newly twenty-two—tired of a year of false promises, and eager for a new year of promising starts. Turned 22 in 2020; 22 in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;margin-left: 25px&quot;&gt;—like we’re twenty-two&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;ive-been-writing-this-essay-on-and-off-since-october-made-flippant-jokes-about-quarantine-existentialism-mulled-over-postgrad-friendships-and-purpose-in-long-texts-and-asked-myself-many-questions-i-still-dont-know-the-answer-to-heres-to-twenty-two&quot;&gt;i’ve been writing this essay on and off since october. made flippant jokes about quarantine existentialism, mulled over postgrad friendships and purpose in long texts, and asked myself many questions i still don’t know the answer to. here’s to twenty-two.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;fin.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">on turning twenty-two in the year 2020. There’s a certain rite of passage when you turn twenty-two. All the major young adult milestones are presumably behind you: you’ve voted in an election, had your first legal drink of alcohol, and graduated from university. Everything ahead of you now exists in the postgraduate limbo called the rest of your life. You also listen to Taylor Swift’s “22” because i don’t know about you, but you wouldn’t really be twenty-two without it. A perfect storm of happy, free, confused, and lonely. Take these last three minutes and twenty seven seconds with your hipster glasses and oversized t-shirts. You may never feel this way again, but everything will be alright if we just keep—</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2020, in review</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020-12/2020-in-review" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2020, in review" /><published>2020-12-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-12-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020-12/2020-in-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020-12/2020-in-review">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;an ordered list of things i really really loved this year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;see my &lt;a href=&quot;https://scrapbook.kellyluo.me/#/&quot;&gt;scrapbook 2020&lt;/a&gt;  for all the stories i consumed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;top-picks&quot;&gt;top picks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tv shows&lt;/strong&gt; (twenty-eight): never have i ever&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;films&lt;/strong&gt; (thirty-three): to all the boys p.s. i still love you&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;books&lt;/strong&gt; (&amp;gt; twenty-five book goal):&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;audio&lt;/strong&gt; (“2014 cottagecore”): folklore by taylor swift&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;guilty pleasures&lt;/strong&gt; (a few here and there): dash &amp;amp; lily&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lukewarm disappointments&lt;/strong&gt;  (too many to count): mulan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tv-shows&quot;&gt;tv shows&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;twenty-eight-tv-shows&quot;&gt;twenty-eight tv shows&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;never have i ever (may 2020)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;love life (june 2020)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the queen’s gambit (oct 2020)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;very honorable mentions because i didn’t pay enough attention in fall 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;when they see us (june 2020), euphoria (aug 2020), looking for alaska (july 2020), high school musical tm : ts (jan 2020), the end of the fucking world (feb 2020), the good place (aug 2020)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;films&quot;&gt;films&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;thirty-three-films&quot;&gt;thirty-three films&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;to all the boys: p.s. i still love you (feb 2020)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;emma. (april 2020)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hamilton (july 2020)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;soul (dec 2020)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;enola holmes (sept 2020)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;i was late to the party, but also really enjoyed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;parasite (may 2019), knives out (july 2020), the portrait of a lady on fire (may 2020), get out (oct 2020), hustlers (jan 2020)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guilty-pleasures&quot;&gt;guilty pleasures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;things-i-cant-believe-i-watched-but-im-not-surprised&quot;&gt;things i can’t believe i watched but i’m not surprised&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dash &amp;amp; lily (nov 2020)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;spinning out (jan 2020)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;emily in paris (oct 2020)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lukewarm-disappointments&quot;&gt;lukewarm disappointments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;things-i-wanted-to-love-but-really-couldnt-like-this-year&quot;&gt;things i wanted to love but really couldn’t (like this year)&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mulan (sept 2020)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;survivor 40: winners at war (feb - apr 2020)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;subpar netflix christmas films&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">an ordered list of things i really really loved this year. see my scrapbook 2020 for all the stories i consumed. top picks tv shows (twenty-eight): never have i ever films (thirty-three): to all the boys p.s. i still love you books (&amp;gt; twenty-five book goal): audio (“2014 cottagecore”): folklore by taylor swift guilty pleasures (a few here and there): dash &amp;amp; lily lukewarm disappointments (too many to count): mulan</summary></entry></feed>