<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-09-12T23:31:57-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">recollectives</title><subtitle>a blog by kelly luo</subtitle><entry><title type="html">collections — no. 013</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022-06-24/collections-013" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="collections — no. 013" /><published>2022-06-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-06-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022-06-24/collections-013</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022-06-24/collections-013">&lt;p&gt;I once read that &lt;a href=&quot;https://inkmagician.tumblr.com/post/155262261071/january-yawns-into-existence-tender-mouthed-raw&quot;&gt;months yawn into existence&lt;/a&gt;—like a sharp inhale of untamed time that burns out of you as the days amble into weeks. That’s what it feels like to make it to June: the contagion of one yawn after the other, when half the year gets lost behind and the remaining half unfurls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This collection is about girlhood, womanhood; a future that is female as much as it is fleeting and fickle. A reminder that it is only June, and the worst is not over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;i know how this ends&lt;/strong&gt;: today, the headline said the end is here&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hello girl&lt;/strong&gt;: clean girl, material girl, &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; girl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;💌&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-know-how-this-ends&quot;&gt;i know how this ends&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;today-the-headline-said-the-end-is-here&quot;&gt;today, the headline said the end is here&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was raised on the brand of self-righteous, barely-intersectional feminism that was eager to inspire on movie screens, the kind that promised braids and a side of bravery could topple unchecked despots and archaic regimes. She wasn’t like the other girls because she could still be scared, but wielded her vulnerability with the virtue of grit. She could tough it out, shoulder the burden, and take on the world when it was against her. And she would win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up this morning, on June 24th, and thought about the generation of girls who knew the stories of a girl against the world. Who clung to notions that they could save themselves and others if they stood taller and stared harder. Who could change the world someday, if the world let her. But the world, &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; world, always crushes the girl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sovereignty of the dystopia isn’t waiting for us in an untouchable, far-off future. It sits in a classical building high up on a hill, twisting its hands and thinking it knows best. Its machinations are little pulses of seismic activity: small earthquakes that tremble into full-blown natural disasters across the social topography. For a long while, we’ve felt the ground sinking beneath our feet. Today, it’s swallowing us whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The legend of David v. Goliath persists because when David falls, he gets to get back up. No bruises on his knee or gashes on his palm. Unscathed. When laws and institutions and an entire judicial system fail the girl, she becomes the failure. Judicial precedent cannot save her; somebody made up that word once in old French, and now, precedent is just another word for a stone left unturned. Sometimes, she wonders if precedent is just the word that cowards use when they’re scared to face the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up this morning, looked at my phone, and wanted to go back to sleep. I wanted to return to my body, but it doesn’t really belong to us anymore, does it. Maybe that’s what those movies were trying to tell us all along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;anyway, read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2022/07/04/we-are-not-going-back-to-the-time-before-roe-we-are-going-somewhere-worse&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; by jia tolentino.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hello-girl&quot;&gt;hello girl&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;clean-girl-material-girl-that-girl&quot;&gt;clean girl, material girl, &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; girl&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;preface&lt;/em&gt;: This is probably part of a longer essay: a piece about girlhood and what that uniquely means to every girl, and the girls we want to be in the forming stage and the girls we’ve become in the norming stage. The dominant theme is the fracturing. The splintered creation and demolition of various personas, enforced by societal and cultural expectations, that condense into the palatable version of a normal girl. The ideas here explore some of the containers the girls have been put in, and why they’re leaders in their category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early aughts, the &lt;em&gt;it&lt;/em&gt; girl was all the rage. She was an heiress to a small family fortune, who set the tone of what was in (and what was out) with avant-garde looks and ruled the social scene with her a manicured fist of influence. The &lt;em&gt;it&lt;/em&gt; girl let her privilege radiate out of her pores, wore it like her best perfume. If she wasn’t well-liked, she was thoroughly envied. An aura personified as the popular girl in teen films or the cover model of grocery store tabloids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, the &lt;em&gt;it&lt;/em&gt; girl became ringarde, too tacky and insincere for a societal order that prized authenticity. A reactionary counterculture swooped in for the girls next door. More girls filed in after: skater girl, boss girl, lulu girl, granola girl, sad girl. Fast-forward to the modern girls of today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The material girl likes material things, the fancy clothes and expensive cosmetics the &lt;em&gt;it&lt;/em&gt; girl prized, but now with the down-to-earth awareness about her self-indulgence. The credit card bears her name: she owns what she buys. She buys luxury handbags and linen bedding because she can, because they make her feel great; so why should she be faulted for liking nice things? Why should any girl be ashamed of wanting nice things? The corporatization of femininity is consecrated as a viable business model, but  maybe the material girl wields her material power as an exercise of personal capital. Her things are not what make her valuable, but rather, she treasures her valuables because of her inherent sense of self-worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clean girl is effortless. She practically floats on air, and when she doesn’t float, she dons athleisure and performs yoga in a hot studio. She wears makeup, but just so her cheeks embrace a soft rosy glow and her lips glisten with a barely-there rouge. Only so her natural beauty can shine through; she’s beautiful inside and out. Cleaning is not a chore, but a cleansing ritual that brings her in harmony with her surroundings. Her cleaning supplies are probably non-toxic, biodegradable. There’s extra spinach in her morning smoothies. She is untouchable in the way she ensures nothing harmful could ever come her way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That&lt;/em&gt; girl has her shit together. She bullet journals her life into action and drinks matcha lattes in the morning; maybe goes out for an afternoon run and sleeps after a multi-step skincare routine. She never forgets to water her plants and takes vitamins like clockwork. She’s never gotten a bad grade on a test because she treats every day like a new test; she is constantly being tested and she is passing with flying colors. She doesn’t want to conquer (that’s the boss girl), she simply wants control. She takes all the messy inertia of life and makes it work for her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some day, these girls will grow up; or maybe they are already grown, but we have a nasty habit of infantilizing women. We press them between pages of dress codes and social etiquette, and hope they’re preserved in perfect condition when we’re done. They may grow up and read the headlines. They may be grown and listen behind closed doors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s almost worse is how easy it is to become a picture-perfect recreation of these model girls. It’s easy with the right capital to architect the right lifestyle. All that’s required is buying the right things to compose the tableau. A three-thousand dollar handbag; or a closet full of leggings; a leather-bound lined journal. Buy these things, and you’ll become her, approximate. Share the things you buy, and you’ll inspire others to be more like you. A pessimist sees a capitalist flywheel; an optimist sees an empire. Girls see nice things and wonder why they can’t have them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-past-month&quot;&gt;this past month&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;watched&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;the summer i turned pretty&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;not watching:&lt;/strong&gt; the fleabag-ification of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fz7HmgPJQak&quot;&gt;persuasion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;read&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;book lovers&lt;/em&gt; by emily henry
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;such a smart book. knows the tropes of a small town romance and plays those cards so well.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;listening&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;the summer i turned pretty&lt;/em&gt; soundtrack could hardly be more perfect if it tried—taylor, bleachers, olivia, phoebe, carly. &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; bon iver. plus billie and ariana just for kicks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I once read that months yawn into existence—like a sharp inhale of untamed time that burns out of you as the days amble into weeks. That’s what it feels like to make it to June: the contagion of one yawn after the other, when half the year gets lost behind and the remaining half unfurls. This collection is about girlhood, womanhood; a future that is female as much as it is fleeting and fickle. A reminder that it is only June, and the worst is not over. i know how this ends: today, the headline said the end is here hello girl: clean girl, material girl, that girl 💌</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">collections — no. 012</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022-06-04/collections-012" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="collections — no. 012" /><published>2022-06-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-06-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022-06-04/collections-012</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022-06-04/collections-012">&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while. Below are my missed synaptic connections, thoughts I’ve turned over and over in newly-formed neurons but couldn’t quite electrify into fully-functioning thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;i’ll make a myth out of you&lt;/strong&gt;: make me into something better; or pretend i’m someone better&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;a table set for you and who&lt;/strong&gt;: an invitation into harry’s house&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here’s the succession plot&lt;/strong&gt;: can we stop renewing this for another season&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;💌&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ill-make-a-myth-out-of-you&quot;&gt;i’ll make a myth out of you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s summer in New York. Muggy skies, sweltering humidity. I like writing about the seasons, the constant change with a recognizable face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the spring wrapped up in the most famous of abduction myths, Hades and Persephone and the melodramatic way the Greeks explained away the despair of a season. My understanding of the tale was caked with assumptions: what I knew from Homer’s source material through countless reinterpretations by classical scholars and antiquity fans. I had to dust off canon from criticism, and revel in the lack of fact in myth: I’ve found my own interpretation in the sea of stories and there’s something comforting in that we all have a branch of myth that we believe in and carry with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I’m writing this now, when the spring has bloomed and summer is not yet ripe, because I spent the past few months spinning these sensibilities in my head in search of meaning. I have two working theories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;theory-i-make-me-into-something-better&quot;&gt;theory i: make me into something better&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is the the promise of escapist transformation. For Gawker, Jenny Zhang wrote “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gawker.com/culture/mythology-legend-lore-kid-childhood-obsession-traditional-tales&quot;&gt;Forget Horse Girls, Embrace the Mythology Freak&lt;/a&gt;” last fall, and these ideas make a weary sort of sense. The antiquity poets and orators were obsessed with transformation; they wrote it into the tragic tales of characters and promised it would reveal something truer about the divinity within someone. That perhaps they were more or lesser than all along. For the rest of us, it’s one of those things where you had to have been there to know what it really meant; something contradictory about how the Greek stories were so unkind to women but the nebulous forces of girlhood molded us closer to a mythic past: “I would trace the contours of an alternate reality in my mind and envision where I could fit in, the new roles and selves I could inhabit.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our lives are so simple. I am realizing (now) we spend most of our postgraduate existence reckoning with how unremarkable our lives are, and we weigh ourselves down with the stones of denial and continue to swim against the current toward elusive novelty. &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/culture-desk/can-greek-tragedy-get-us-through-the-pandemic&quot;&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; did an excellent elaboration of Greek tragedy as a coping mechanism during the pandemic, and I’m reminded that theatre is merely a projection of feelings we’re too scared to have as humans. Instead, we dress them up in the vilest of situations. Gods and monsters. This is my misplaced nostalgia rearing its head; the reason why we first hear a myth as a child and it still haunts us when we grow up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“But often there is no existence-altering transformation, no magical shifting of skin and bone, spirit and soul; you discover that it’s merely yourself staring back at you from the fold. To go from a lore child to a lore adult is a crushing, drawn-out process of realizing the mundanity of most existences.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;theory-ii-pretend-im-someone-better&quot;&gt;theory ii: pretend i’m someone better&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second is a perverse approximation of cultural capital. Nothing screams well-cultured and well-read like a comfortable familiarity with the religious rites of Western civilization. To cite references to these gods is to speak the secret language passed through lineages that are not yours. I can make my citations, but I will never make it all the way to the pinnacle of the Western canon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Possessors of high cultural capital don’t read &lt;em&gt;Percy Jackson&lt;/em&gt;; they were tutored in Latin when young and grew up in halls adorned with marble statues. Someone said the Greeks had importance, and that importance became the bedrock of the West, and then their stories became codified in scholarship. This is the prestige that Hades and Persephone and spring carry. When we hear the myth for the first time, the humanities are made accessible and resonant to the far caches of society. We continue listening because it maintains the appearance of a learned person; the exclusive luxury of familiar knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love articulations of high versus low culture, because that’s the inner conflict of cultural criticism’s existential existence (what is culture? who gets to criticize it? what critiques are valid and uplifted?). It’s a tension that plucks taut in the in-between spaces of the educated elite and corporate glamour. You’re supposed to be well-versed in &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Iliad&lt;/em&gt; in stuffy dining hall discussions, but you should also go to the beach with a copy of Madeline Miller’s &lt;em&gt;Circe.&lt;/em&gt; (As an aside and unsolicited book review, I finally hate-finished &lt;em&gt;Circe&lt;/em&gt; out of duty. It was fine. I think she gets a lot of undue praise for her poetic eloquence, when her prose is simply good, sometimes great. There are occasionally breathtaking lines, but she writes overall in a very restrained tradition.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have started, and have only ever gotten a few chapters into, Donna Tartt’s &lt;em&gt;The Secret History&lt;/em&gt;, but that’s the vibe. The cover features a marble bust of a figure that only could have been important enough to be carved into stone. It represents the smooth classical curves of a culture that was here long before we were, and will endure long after we are gone. We get close. We get close by reading the sources and fixating on characters and dropping references when it suits us. These old stories are still held in esteem because they are divine mirrors of who we are and we keep reaching out toward them. Maybe if we insist upon it enough, we can claw our way to belonging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-table-set-for-you-and-who&quot;&gt;a table set for you and who&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;an-invitation-into-harrys-house&quot;&gt;an invitation into harry’s house&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the the Harry Styles album review that literally nobody asked for. We’re in &lt;em&gt;Harry’s House&lt;/em&gt;, sitting in his living room listening to this album on vinyl with a glass of sparkling wine. No lede of music review has brought me greater joy than this one in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pitchfork.com/reviews/albums/harry-styles-harrys-house/&quot;&gt;Pitchfork&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: “When a teen idol becomes a rock star, he announces it with a &lt;em&gt;Rolling Stone&lt;/em&gt; spread […] When a rock star becomes a lifestyle influencer, he announces it with a &lt;em&gt;Better Homes &amp;amp; Gardens&lt;/em&gt; cover.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no one more surprised than I was two-and-a-half years ago when I sat down and listened to Harry’s sophomore album, &lt;em&gt;Fine Line&lt;/em&gt;, at length and became a fan of his music. I still think &lt;em&gt;Fine Line&lt;/em&gt; is a modern masterpiece and Harry has entered the select echelon of musicians where I could sing along to almost all of the discography during a live performance. &lt;em&gt;Harry’s House&lt;/em&gt; is calmer; less morose than &lt;em&gt;Fine Line&lt;/em&gt; and less bombastic than his debut, &lt;em&gt;Harry Styles&lt;/em&gt;. This album has dominated my Spotify rotation for the last two weeks, and so I’m here to make sense of what I’m hearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curated domesticity envelopes this album; and make no mistake, he wrote this in the cozy blanket of indoor quarantine vibes. If Taylor’s &lt;em&gt;folklore&lt;/em&gt; stopped lighting candles in the woods after midnight and turned on the diffuser by the reading nook instead to produce Harry’s &lt;em&gt;Harry’s House&lt;/em&gt;. I have learned one truth from the most recent Harry Styles album cycle: he is not a good lyricist. But that’s okay. He has a great voice and an even better production team; amplified by lots of suave charisma and rocker flair that carry his sound further than other contemporary young male artists. The lyrics on this album aren’t great, largely relying on repetitive hooks and clipped imagery to invoke sensation. That’s cozy quarantine vibes, I guess—just vibe, sparse substance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;house highlights&lt;/em&gt;: daylight, satellite, late night talking, as it was, keep driving&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;house goodlights&lt;/em&gt;: grapejuice, little freak, cinema, matilda, music for a sushi restaurant&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;house lowlights&lt;/em&gt;: daydreaming, boyfriends, love of my life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;heres-the-succession-plot&quot;&gt;here’s the succession plot&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;can-we-stop-renewing-this-for-another-season&quot;&gt;can we stop renewing this for another season&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a matter of months, we’ve watched three shows about brilliant tech founders creating and destroying their fortunes. Something Adam, something Elizabeth, something Travis. It must be fascinating when the glamour and luxury of tech only exists as an app on the phone or within a &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; expose; and most, if not all, people, are completely detached from the drama. They love the schemes and solitaire. But it all feels so provincial, parochial even, when you’re one of those tiny people in the big office building looking up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;em&gt;New Yorker&lt;/em&gt; feature said it better about modern grifter series, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2022/04/04/the-comforts-of-wecrashed-and-the-modern-grifter-series&quot;&gt;“True Grift”&lt;/a&gt;: “Bad Entrepreneur TV, even when it’s good, makes for more antiseptic viewing than earlier antihero sagas.” They call it comfort food. That we’re not stupid; that it’s the hubris of capitalism portrayed by attractive celebrity counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t have much to say or show for the past few months of succession spring except to say, it’s not comfort food. It’s tonic water. It is bitter and unappetizing. It sours everything around it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;these-past-months&quot;&gt;these past months&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;watched&lt;/strong&gt;: if haven’t recommended &lt;em&gt;bridgerton&lt;/em&gt; season 02 yet, then i haven’t spoken to you since last year&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;read&lt;/strong&gt;: this is a series of essays published in the last few months about vibes and places that i enjoyed as a call and response; and i still don’t really get the vibe shift
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instapaper.com/read/1484056255&quot;&gt;a vibe shift is coming&lt;/a&gt;” by alison p. davis&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instapaper.com/read/1509164155&quot;&gt;escape from dimes square&lt;/a&gt;” by will harris&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://dirt.substack.com/p/dirt-nowhere-or-new-york&quot;&gt;nowhere or new york&lt;/a&gt;” by drew austin&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;listened&lt;/strong&gt;:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/3je5eo6UE6S874LPJJdyEm?si=57b70ba9ad93476f&quot;&gt;girls against god&lt;/a&gt;,” florence + the machine&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/4SKvKJaqkRl1bUZWEqTYzl?si=7651e3bf28284ba3&quot;&gt;sidelines&lt;/a&gt;,” phoebe bridgers&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/5411TEB6tlzvuF5A4oyldr?si=a7a2c0f8ebe64a22&quot;&gt;francis forever&lt;/a&gt;,” mitski&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;quoted&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“talking about the weather is a way to acknowledge how absurd it is that time passes and yet here we are, standing in the middle of it, mixing memory and desire.”
—”&lt;a href=&quot;https://griefbacon.substack.com/p/fools-spring&quot;&gt;fool’s spring&lt;/a&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It’s been a while. Below are my missed synaptic connections, thoughts I’ve turned over and over in newly-formed neurons but couldn’t quite electrify into fully-functioning thoughts. i’ll make a myth out of you: make me into something better; or pretend i’m someone better a table set for you and who: an invitation into harry’s house here’s the succession plot: can we stop renewing this for another season 💌</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">she forgot a little thing called spring</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022-04-12/persephone-and-hades-send-their-best-from-the-underworld" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="she forgot a little thing called spring" /><published>2022-04-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-04-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022-04-12/persephone%20and%20hades%20send%20their%20best%20from%20the%20underworld</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022-04-12/persephone-and-hades-send-their-best-from-the-underworld">&lt;h6 id=&quot;persephone-and-hades-send-their-best-from-the-underworld&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;persephone and hades send their best from the underworld&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a spring foccaccia recently—sliced up bell peppers as sun rays, halved cherry tomatoes into flower petals, planted artichokes in towering stalks—a story of the season told through fresh produce and processed grain. I summoned spring in a four-hundred and fifty degree gas oven and brought it with me as an offering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The March solstice has passed over us, and the Eleusinian Mysteries made elusive promises that Demeter and Persephone would make their return to the overworld. That spring, in all of its verdant glory, would soon emerge from the winter frost. The trees in San Francisco glow a little greener in the early morning, and the warm sun has peaked out from the fog enough days to solicit endless weekends of picnicking in the dewy grass. If winter is a Faustian bargain, then spring is a contract we made with a gentler god. Spring is a promise of renewal; hope blossoms to fill the empty spaces our bodies left behind in the snow. When spring arrives, we find reason to find our faith again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-give-me-liberty-or-bring-me-the-dead&quot;&gt;i. give me liberty, or bring me the dead&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spring comes to the overworld because Hades and Persephone struck a bargain with the rest of the pantheon: when Persphone reunites with her mother above, the world blooms; when Persephone reunites with her husband below, the world shrivels. Much has been written in scholarship about the Hades and Persephone myth (of both the academic and amateur kind). We retell the stories of seasons through these two: one of loss, betrayal, and love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hades and Persephone have captured the creative imagination, and this spring, I can’t help but wonder why—why a fixcation on the cyclic ending of a tragic pairing engenders a fascination with the comings and goings of a fertile season. The modern romance genre can trace its lineage back to the romanticization of Hades and Persephone. Restated in more desireable tropes, Hades is a reformed bad boy and Persephone is a good girl turned gone (perhaps even a manic pixie dream girl). It’s the contrast of dark and light that endures, and the enchanting complexity of a darkness has been wrongfully misunderstood in his good intentions and a lightness who has craved chaos and destruction to spite her golden handcuffs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick online search reveals a littany of retellings borne out of the mythical Greek canon about the royal couple of the Underworld. This is a reading of Hades, as ruler of the dead (not of death; an important distinction), who deserves redemption in the softened edges of his fury. He’s a tragic and tortured figure who holds the afterlife with a cruel iron grip. He is deadly, but not death. He is dignified but not the devil; even the ancient Greek conception of the underworld was not quite the torment of Hell. There is an efficient pragmatism in the cool and collected operation of his kingdom, where he is despised and ostracized by the living when he simply finds duty in the cards he was dealt. His grip grows into an embrace when Persephone emerges, picking flowers in a green meadow. For all his misfortune and misery, Persephone is promise that Hades may be worthy of joy in his life too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is also a reading of Persephone, as innocent maiden turned dread queen, who had a kind soul yet vicious disposition. In the overworld, she is the graceful embodiment of fertility and vegetation; her given name, Kore, is an expression of fair maidenhood. The protective shield of her doting mother may have done her more harm than good, where her dalliance with the king of the dead is cast as a defiant streak of rebellion. This myth is also a tale of a mother’s love, but Demeter is a catalyst as much as she is the aggrieved. She is granted the credit of agency in the impossible situation of a kidnapping. Persephone was a sheltered girl who grew into a powerful woman, and when she married Hades, she lost her youthful whimsy but earned a kingdom instead. In the underworld, she is Persephone, bringer of death. She and her husband rule the lost, passed-on souls ferried across the Styx. Within the barren darkness of her adopted realm, Persephone exudes light and generosity; and in the absence of her birth realm, the fields and flowers shrivel and decay in anticipation of her return. These abandoned souls may soon feel warmth again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ii-deathless-deathful-death-struck&quot;&gt;ii. deathless, deathful, death struck&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a poem about Persephone, she is described as “deathless, deathful, death struck.” Lest anyone forget her namesake as bringer of death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one of my all-time favorite Elisabeth Hewer pieces, the first in her “&lt;a href=&quot;https://elisabethhewer.co.uk/post/133202476251/hades-you-look-like-the-summer-sun-i-could-live.&quot;&gt;the greek tragedy i’ll never write&lt;/a&gt;” series, Hades pleads. His hearts wants what it wants, and it wants her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://snipboard.io/hbHgER.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&amp;quot;the greek tradgedy i'll never write&amp;quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/1J1yxODbNlqKbwRqJxYJUP?si=b0jQ4L5VQWylW--SwaFrtA&quot;&gt;Hadestown&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; the folk opera (requisite &lt;a href=&quot;https://elisabethhewer.co.uk/post/133202476251/hades-you-look-like-the-summer-sun-i-could-live&quot;&gt;NPR Tiny Desk Concert&lt;/a&gt; listening) retells how Hades and Persephone fall in and out of love to the acclaim of multiple Tony’s. Spring languishes as Persephone grudgingly takes the train back to her seasonal duties, and her reunions with Hades are only a glimmer of their former sparkle. Yet she surfaces the kindness and grace in his kingship, and thus Orpheus and Eurydice are granted a second chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a recent fixation of mine (and arguably, the reason I have thought enough to write this in the first place) the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webtoons.com/en/romance/lore-olympus/list?title_no=1320&amp;amp;page=1&quot;&gt;webcomic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Lore Olympus&lt;/em&gt; inspires a Hellenic urban fantasy. It’s an inspired illustration of the pantheon with a modern twist, and Hades and Persephone radiate in their vibrant blue-pink hues. Hades as a king-businessman with a cool exterior hiding a complete nervous-wreck; Persephone as a young, naïve goddess marred by melancholy and wrath. The art is indulgent and lush, and for whatever it is in comic form, the fantastical digital paintstrokes make it a breathtaking read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this &lt;a href=&quot;https://boykeats.tumblr.com/post/129425629587/dictionary-poem-x-by-keaton-st-james&quot;&gt;dictionary&lt;/a&gt; definition, pomegrantes grant agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://64.media.tumblr.com/340150cf70e15fa3ce8aaa1ceb30110f/tumblr_nuxlmlVEQ81ue441bo1_r1_500.png&quot; alt=&quot;pomegranate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">persephone and hades send their best from the underworld I made a spring foccaccia recently—sliced up bell peppers as sun rays, halved cherry tomatoes into flower petals, planted artichokes in towering stalks—a story of the season told through fresh produce and processed grain. I summoned spring in a four-hundred and fifty degree gas oven and brought it with me as an offering. The March solstice has passed over us, and the Eleusinian Mysteries made elusive promises that Demeter and Persephone would make their return to the overworld. That spring, in all of its verdant glory, would soon emerge from the winter frost. The trees in San Francisco glow a little greener in the early morning, and the warm sun has peaked out from the fog enough days to solicit endless weekends of picnicking in the dewy grass. If winter is a Faustian bargain, then spring is a contract we made with a gentler god. Spring is a promise of renewal; hope blossoms to fill the empty spaces our bodies left behind in the snow. When spring arrives, we find reason to find our faith again.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">interlude: before the spring</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022-03-10/seasons-twenty-two" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="interlude: before the spring" /><published>2022-03-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-03-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022-03-10/seasons-twenty-two</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022-03-10/seasons-twenty-two">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/interludes.png&quot; alt=&quot;&amp;quot;interlude: before the spring&amp;quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a momentary pause from irregularly scheduled programming. I share some of what I’ve been reading, ramble about what I want to write, and list other possible endeavors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sharp-artifacts&quot;&gt;sharp artifacts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been reading a lot about writing recently (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/56824/tell-all-the-truth-but-tell-it-slant-1263?utm_campaign=kellyluo&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=Revue newsletter&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;tell the truth but tell it slant&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), and the themes of craft recur in my brain like a self-conscious broken record. I’ve been thinking about what makes good writing: if my own writing is ever good (and if it is any good, how did I get here? how many years of schooling and essays written and books read have given me this canon?—and if it’s not, well, I suppose I’m pontificating and out of luck here); or if the writers I admire found the courage to say the things I simply do not have the words for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m here to make the audacious claim that some people have really bad prose. Most can write, surely, but it’s didactic and bland. There’s no soul; only coherent logic and pragmatic structure. Their writing is akin to robotic transcription. Functional, yet unfeeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good writers can write, but great writers can wound. They cut you open. Their words are sharp and legible, and in turn, you bleed feelings and memories and psyche. Call it resonance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stumbling upon a striking piece of prose is finding a gem in the archeological landfill of human thought. As I read (in the infinite sprawl of internet content), I collect what others have written and catalogue them in a library of artifacts I wish I had the talent to write myself. I thought it’d be nice to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some sentences that cut me open in the last three months:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“A mosaic is a conversation between what is broken.”—&lt;em&gt;finding beauty in a broken world&lt;/em&gt;, terry tempest williams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“I don’t ever talk about it. It’s a bit like a little malformed myth still lodged between my heart and my rib cage.”—”&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.guernicamag.com/woven&quot;&gt;woven&lt;/a&gt;”, lidia yuknavitch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“We want to know how people get close to each other, and how they break apart, what they promise each other and how they fail at those promises, what they want from each other and what happens when they get it.”— “&lt;a href=&quot;https://griefbacon.substack.com/p/eavesdropping&quot;&gt;evesdropping&lt;/a&gt;”, helena fitzgerald&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Real art is specific. Particular. It has its own localities. It traces them obsessively. It’s more than just a style. It is a way of seeing. Being.”—”&lt;a href=&quot;https://blgtylr.substack.com/p/happy-accommodations&quot;&gt;happy accomodations&lt;/a&gt;”, brandon taylor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-day-job&quot;&gt;the day job&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was asked recently to describe the kind of writing I do in my daily life, if at all. I described my writing at work as business writing: it spans the transactional to the generative. Transactional in the slack messages and email replies and document comments; a treadmill of following-up on loose ends and exchanging feedback. Generative in the product documentation that establishes the setting of a problem and charts a storyline to resolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing at work is finding form for a different kind of fiction. It forces concision into boxes of resource optimization and short-attention spans. But it’s also boundless in the way ideas start from nothing and wind their way to something. Most of the time it can be boring, but when done well, it’s fantastical. It’s enchanting to dream up a world where someone’s life is made (marginally) better through the divine intervention of software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I do write a sizeable quantity at work. Words pour out of me in every corner and crevice. A lot of it isn’t any good (so say the Google Doc comments), but some of it occasionally feels like striking gold. I hadn’t thought much about this until I considered the twisted irony of spending most of my college years running away from small-group sections and convincing myself that I loved calculus. Though, hand on heart, the Navier-Stokes equations are a gorgeous physical wonder, if I still remembered how to solve them. All I do these days is write, apparently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;let-me-write-you-an-email&quot;&gt;let me write you an email&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m writing &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; because I’m avoiding the other writing I have to do. The words are harder to find and I haven’t done the requisite thinking to begin the hunt. Until then, here’s my roadmap:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;some proposals, the work-kind-of-writing, that I’m overdue for in the first half of the year. a few goals depend on the constant tension of wanting to finish the thing and desperately needing to summon the energy to do it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a longer writing project; ten pages. the closest I’ll get to cracking myself open on the page.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a eulogy for the two-year anniversary of a certain day in March. I started writing this last year and couldn’t bring myself to get any further in the details; though my memories are fuzzier now (two years), it’s an exorcism I owe to myself. maybe this will be the March.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a list of goodbyes. I might see some of these people again soon (and I don’t really know if I want to; perhaps).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;some essay about the lyric “and I wake up in the middle of the night / it’s like I can feel time moving” from “&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/01K4zKU104LyJ8gMb7227B?si=ec10e573879c47dc&amp;amp;utm_campaign=kellyluo&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=Revue newsletter&quot;&gt;nothing new&lt;/a&gt;” because I was at the end of twenty-two and that realization sent me spinning for a while.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;maybe emails. I’m chronically terrible at texting / posting in short-form, but emails are a careful craft. The sustained intimacy of mail-order communication. I’ll write you an email if you just ask; it’ll go a lot like this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stay-tuned-for&quot;&gt;stay tuned for&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the spring season, I will:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;make a lavender-scented candle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;seal an envelope with hot wax&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mould a decorative object&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;design a typographic poster&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;acquire more postcards&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hike up a steeper hill&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather will soon turn warmer, and I will rekindle the warmth of possibility.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is a momentary pause from irregularly scheduled programming. I share some of what I’ve been reading, ramble about what I want to write, and list other possible endeavors.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">collections — no. 011</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022-02-25/collections-011" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="collections — no. 011" /><published>2022-02-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-02-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022-02-25/collections-011</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022-02-25/collections-011">&lt;h6 id=&quot;collections-a-semi-seasonal-reset&quot;&gt;collections: a semi-seasonal reset&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a weird week, so this is some writing about writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;semi-fictitious:&lt;/strong&gt; so you want to write about the real thing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;english class canons&lt;/strong&gt;: let the people read what they want&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;disorganized thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;: from the incomplete drafts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;💌&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;semi-fictitious&quot;&gt;semi-fictitious&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;so-you-want-to-write-about-the-real-thing&quot;&gt;so you want to write about the real thing&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the best and worst of my teen years, I wrote a lot of fiction. Mostly short sketches of situations and characters, anything I could plot down within one to two pages of a Word document and abandon forever. It was easier then than it is now. It was easier to dream up people and places interacting when I had a incipient sense of how the world worked (and those senses are still nascent, for the record). So imagined it was almost real. When I dig back into my archives, I roll my eyes in the &lt;em&gt;can you believe I wrote this&lt;/em&gt; kind of way, at the cloying and saccharine sentiments of purple prose. The prose is still purple, but hopefully a sharper mauve these days. I’ve impatiently migrated those words across many third-party services over the years—from blogspot to tumblr to whatever newsletter platform is the rage—and I’ve settled for a simple markdown editor in the present. I’ll notice the time stamp (eight years ago), and the time is gone but the words stand still.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last full piece of fiction I wrote is dated August 29th, 2018. The cruel irony is that I wrote the entirety of it listening to Fall Out Boy’s &lt;em&gt;American Beauty/American Psycho&lt;/em&gt; album; it had felt appropriate in the misguided compulsion to write subversive, modern Americana. We’re going to skip over the part where only three people have read this seventeen-page dual POV monstrosity, and one of those readers was an actual respected writer. I was deluded enough to think this held any merit. I was very clearly imitating a style I wanted to write, but had no business in portraying. It’s amusing to revisit now (and find the few hidden gems in the knockoff paragraphs), because I wrote a cliché about a writer and a subject. And when you write about a writer, that writer has to pontificate about writing too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the climax, this is what my wordsmith had to say: “As a writer, he is familiar with the frazzled, torturous clawing in his chest when he is searching for the right word. The word escapes him, torments him. It reaches the tip of his tongue but fizzles out before he can reach for a dictionary. The panic rises because the sentence is incomplete, and punctuation cannot wrap around an unfinished sentence with a gaping wound.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fiction got harder when imagined people got less real; and non-fiction got better when time made everything else more real. The evolution compounded when I had lived a little longer and the assembly of those lived experiences stare back at me every time the cursor blinks on a blank page. It really is easier to think and write about what you know. Fiction was easy because the words could be invented to describe contrived feelings, yet once you know how they actually feel, you need to search for the words that do them justice. It becomes an anthropological dig.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m doing the &lt;em&gt;writerly&lt;/em&gt; thing where instead of writing about anything of substance, I’m writing about the things I’ve read and writing itself. Because writing makes you fundamentally opinionated about how the words are smithed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in writing &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt;, I surfaced two pieces from my reading backlog: Parul Seghal’s keenly-observed “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instapaper.com/read/1471005350/18660659&quot;&gt;The Case Against the Trauma Plot&lt;/a&gt;” and Brandon Taylor’s blithe response, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://blgtylr.substack.com/p/emotional-support-trauma-plot&quot;&gt;emotional support trauma plot&lt;/a&gt;,” which I may have enjoyed reading more than the original. Here’s the quote I haven’t been able to shake loose from my brain:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Fiction is, I think, always kind of about the shock of human experience. The shock of being alive.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been shocked quite a few times in this lifetime; every day is a shock to the system, in the million tiny miracles it takes to be alive. Shell-shocked into waking, into more writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;english-class-canons&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;english class canons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;let-the-people-read-what-they-want&quot;&gt;let the people read what they want&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a pretentious bit about my longstanding regret of not taking more literature classes. I think about this whenever I remember how much time I spent in them during high school, and knew I liked them then but truly value them now. Something about high school English teachers leaving an indelible imprint on our inchoate psyche.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I say this to myself, repeatedly, stewing in the &lt;em&gt;could-have-been&lt;/em&gt; when I know I definitely don’t think I’d enjoy sitting through an entire semester’s literature class now. Those classes are filled to the brim with book after book, and it’s too much reading in a compact space to be motivated to keep up with it week-after-week. The very good punchline here is that I’m not well-read at all. I haven’t read most canonical texts of classical and contemporary culture (see: junior year of high school, &lt;a href=&quot;https://stuy.entest.org/apps/pages/?uREC_ID=128041&amp;amp;type=d&amp;amp;termREC_ID=&amp;amp;pREC_ID=264066&quot;&gt;Contemps &amp;amp; Classics&lt;/a&gt;), and managed to evade the bulk of it in my schooling (meaning: I did not deliberately seek them out; and so I remain as uncultured as ever). I’ve amassed enough of the references that I can tell you what they’re supposed to allude to, but can’t cite any of the source material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I think I actually miss about English classes were the generative parts of it. The part where I read and analyzed texts, or locked myself down with my computer for hours to pour out original thoughts in a double-spaced essay of forms. I missed listening to the beats that others paid attention to, the things I missed the first time around. I would’ve been a terrible English concentrator, but I still entertain the fantasy repertoire of classes and classics. I’d find a new thesis in the mire of a revered work, and someone would have to parse and attempt to understand my re-interpretation in all its tired originality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me wax poetic here and talk about literary criticism through the lens of functional critique. Every paper I’ve written about a novel and text conversation I’ve had about a piece of media has emerged from the same directive—find something new in something old. The context won’t change, but your interpretation of it can. Here’s a bad example: there is literally nothing new to be said about Fitzgerald’s omnipotent and synesthetic green light, but there is a point of discussion around Taylor Swift’s invocation of Gatsby references in her lyricism. The mirrored practice of calling upon a Great American Novel to echo the cultivation of her Great American (Musical) Dynasty. There’s something there, and while nobody cares to discuss this, it’s still fundamentally an interrogation of wealth, and achieving &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; dream, and the beautiful, broken people we aspire to be by the end of it. From there, we go to Min Jin Lee’s foreword for the &lt;em&gt;Penguin Classics&lt;/em&gt; reissue of &lt;em&gt;The Great Gatsby&lt;/em&gt; (she provides an excellent commentary of it in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-new-yorker-interview/what-min-jin-lee-wants-us-to-see&quot;&gt;interview-as-profile&lt;/a&gt;; not in spite of the novel’s faults, but appreciation in light of it: “Recognizing the specificity of Fitzgerald’s choices is a way to read and appraise his work fairly.”) An Asian-American novelist introduces the Great(est) American Novel and guides the next generation on how to read it. This novel isn’t anybody’s true, lived experience, yet we still relish in the mythic Americana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never had the attention span nor the patience to sit and read every book on a syllabus, but I do love syllabi. I love what they stand for: a window into the soul of a well-trodden path. If some faint relative of my soul could speak, it would be in the highlights of words I’ve stolen from others; but here, definitively, is the curated list of origin points. There’s a moral compass to the syllabus. I like to think if I had all the accumulated time in the world, I’d read everything I ought to; yet I’ve had so much of this time, and I’m still nowhere close to making my way through the Classics. They’ve never excited me. I admire them with reverence and respect their significance, but I think the form and function is ultimately more interesting when we reinterpret it. We’re telling the same stories over and over. When we hold something new to the light, in all of its counterfeit glory, and contrast it against the original.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;disorganized-thoughts&quot;&gt;disorganized thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;from-the-incomplete-drafts&quot;&gt;from the incomplete drafts&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world is in disarray once again. Here are some things I wanted to write about, but couldn’t get past the first paragraph:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;typecast&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;ryan atwood talks about crypto&lt;/em&gt;): apparently Ben McKenzie, of Ryan Atwood fame, is a prolific crypto critic on Twitter and this did not hit my radar until the news of his book deal broke. It broke my sense of reality, too, for a moment, because the brooding teen idol of early 2000s Fox was partnering with a renowned journalist to expose the highs and lows of the crypto wave. The cognitive dissonance was weird, because there was nothing disqualifying him from doing this, but my idea of him was permanently cast in this former mold. He was a teen actor, and therefore I couldn’t take him seriously in this endeavour (and well, I couldn’t even write a book about this); no more than I could I take a reality star running for commander in chief seriously. But it’s an incredibly dismissive attitude, because people are capable of holding multiple interests, even if diametrically opposed. He’s more than the job he had at twenty-four.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;new song&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;old song, lost to time&lt;/em&gt;): around december-january, I listened to the duet “&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/3PUMPtOSeXSJsBvK43K96b?si=d14e5bff641645c9&quot;&gt;New Song&lt;/a&gt;” on repeat. I’d queue it up on my way to work and savor every second of the six minutes and twenty-two seconds as Maggie Rogers and Del Water Gap traded off on this soft ballad. They co-created a song they both deeply loved while they were in a banned together, stuffed it in a drawer for nearly a decade as they parted ways—and as the story goes, a stroke of a sonic miracle preserved the original music stems and they were able to remix this track. That is the artifact that lives with us today. This beautiful, wonderful song that never got a name (always referred to as “New Song”), was almost lost to time: but it still endures, and I still listen to it, and it’s almost a complete accident that I get to do this. Life is all the little accidents we call serendipity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wolves&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;carnal, as in, of the flesh&lt;/em&gt;): this came from a train of thought around people and their pets; people love dogs and canine friends and the wolf family. Wolf packs as a metaphor when we don’t actually want to confront a conversation about power, head-on. When I think of wolves, I think of werewolves. The werewolves of the young adult fiction lineage, wherein men (teenage boys) would turn into wolves of the night. I have a themed playlist of songs where &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/3TO6wG55HdfwC8zfOaXAlJ?si=464226784c764f6d&quot;&gt;the wolves&lt;/a&gt; are coincidentally featured in the title. &lt;em&gt;Sharp Teeth&lt;/em&gt; by Tony Barlow is one of my favorite books I’ve never read, written in free-verse about rival werewolf clans in Los Angeles. Wolves as a stand-in for the primal and feral. People are beholden to the sun; wolves are bound to the moon. If dogs reflect the best of modern friendship, then wolves reflect the worst of primitive instincts. Sharp teeth. Razor claws. Lone wolves, loneliness. Power and dominance. Family, feud. Belonging to the pack. Fierce and ferocious. Violence, bloodshed, flesh. Wildness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-past-week&quot;&gt;this past week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;watching&lt;/strong&gt;: still a few episodes behind on euphoria, season 02&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;read&lt;/strong&gt;:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.guernicamag.com/woven/&quot;&gt;woven&lt;/a&gt;” by lydia yuknavitch
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;this is where i learned what it meant to write a braided story. her style is concise but razor-sharp; cuts through her bone and yours.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“Every story I have ever told has a kind of breach to it, I think. You could say that my writing isn’t quite right. That all the beginnings have endings in them.”&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-new-yorker-interview/candace-bushnell-is-back-in-the-city&quot;&gt;candace bushnell is back in the city&lt;/a&gt;” by jia tolentino
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;jia tolentino interviews are always so zesty&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“You mention it in your one-woman show—this desire to write something that people will take seriously. The Great American Novel.”&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;listened&lt;/strong&gt;: mitski. her music is the spring, when some of the flowers are late bloomers and those that were early are now wilted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">collections: a semi-seasonal reset It’s a weird week, so this is some writing about writing. semi-fictitious: so you want to write about the real thing english class canons: let the people read what they want disorganized thoughts: from the incomplete drafts 💌</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">collections — no. 010</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022-02-17/collections-010" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="collections — no. 010" /><published>2022-02-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-02-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022-02-17/collections-010</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022-02-17/collections-010">&lt;h6 id=&quot;collections-a-semi-seasonal-reset&quot;&gt;collections: a semi-seasonal reset&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re in the double digits now and that’s a modern miracle. I was going to spend this collection writing about something else, but then I read “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/infinite-scroll/i-cant-stop-thinking-about-this&quot;&gt;i can’t stop thinking about this&lt;/a&gt;” and, well, these are some things i can’t stop thinking about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;in the pantomime&lt;/strong&gt;: the winter olympics are nothing without canadian ice dancing royalty&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cosmic operas:&lt;/strong&gt; florence + the machine lyrics are something else&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tossed and turned&lt;/strong&gt;: i promised some people i would write about hacky sack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;💌&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-the-pantomime&quot;&gt;in the pantomime&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;the-winter-olympics-are-nothing-without-canadian-ice-dancing-royalty&quot;&gt;the winter olympics are nothing without canadian ice dancing royalty&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a brief blip in 2018, I was obsessed with ice dancing. As in, swept up in the media hype and frenzy around this sport where I barely knew the rules but knew it looked graceful from every angle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“ice dancing is the pinnacle of human achievement”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;—wrote this on a computer sticky note; feb 19, 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ice dancing is a marvel of human achievement (though perhaps not quite the pinnacle, I was being overdramatic). There is an unfathomable degree of athleticism, synchronicity, and elegance involved as you hurl your body in the air with sharp blades attached to your feet—and then trust that the other person will catch you every step of the way atop stone-cold ice. No room for missteps, just the sensuality of knowing your own body so well that it gets mirrored in your partner’s, and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Winter Olympics this year are among the most forgettable: too much has happened and devolved for any of us to consider Beijing 2022 at the forefront of our information diet. But still, the Winter Olympics makes me think of the February from fours year ago when I made a Spotify playlist based on all the songs I’d heard in the free dance, and the description read “um ice dancing has taken over my life and i don’t know how to fix it.” That happened. Twizzles are a real thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some two weeks in February , I was completely invested in Canadian ice dancing royalty, Tessa Virtue and Scott Moir. Had seen every medal-winning performance and behind-the-scenes training montage. Could probably tell you everything about why they were going for Gold during their final performance as a pair in Olympic competition. Knew the refrain of &lt;em&gt;Moulin Rouge&lt;/em&gt; not because Baz Luhrmann created a masterpiece, but because Virtuemoir won their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wOEKdWrtz6U&amp;amp;t=55s&quot;&gt;coveted medal skating to it.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all things that are sparkly and electrically-charged, the Virtuemoir fascination was heighted by the celebrity gossip hype machine. Twitter was a very good place that month; Twitter was on its best behavior for the parasocial fisheye lens in Pyeongchang. We were all over-invested in the personal lives of these two Canadian ice dancers who seemed to destined to be together on- and off- ice. Some select favorites from the February 2018 critics cycle: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theringer.com/olympics/2018/2/19/17021330/tessa-virtue-scott-moir-relationship-winter-olympics&quot;&gt;An Unnecessarily Close Read of the Virtue-Moir Relationship&lt;/a&gt; (the Ringer); &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecut.com/2018/02/are-tessa-virtue-and-scott-moir-dating-olympics-2018.html&quot;&gt;Why Do I Care So Much That These Two Canadian Ice Dancers Aren’t Dating?&lt;/a&gt; (the Cut); and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/culture/2018/2/22/17035136/ice-dancing-relationships-tessa-virtue-scott-moir-dating&quot;&gt;Why people can’t stop shipping Canadian ice dancers Tessa Virtue and Scott Moir&lt;/a&gt; (Vox).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no point to this other than the fact that I find this incredibly funny years later. I was reminded of this recently because the news of #Beijing2022 had dawned upon me, and I was curious what the line of succession looked like after the reigning champions had retired. It has been so long and this has not crossed my mind in ages, and yet my memory can tell you as much as I once knew in the whirlwind of information consumption.  At the end of this very long day, they are two people who became elite athletes in domination of a difficult sport, who both also happen to be attractive, and know full-well how to sell a story. They sold that story for years, and some corner of the internet will still insist they’re in love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Olympics are a pinnacle of parasociality. We lift individuals onto pedestals and claim their story is the story of our nation, our people. We learn their childhoods and traumas, peel back their deepest fears and burning fires, poke and prod them beneath hot camera lights until their face lights up every local newsstand. Their stories, their relationships, their victories—they belong to us. Everything but their failures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll end here with this ice dancing video I’ve forced too many people to watch: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eysNtspIDWs&quot;&gt;Tessa Virtue and Scott Moir skate to Stay by Rihanna&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cosmic-operas&quot;&gt;cosmic operas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;florence--the-machine-lyrics-are-something-else-entirely&quot;&gt;florence + the machine lyrics are something else entirely&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I owe a lot of what I know about writing to Florence + the Machine lyrics. I mean this in the way I could crack open the lyric booklet to the first two Florence albums, and start to trace the lineage of how I write and think today, in the pseudo-poetic way. In voicing the otherwise unperturbed recesses of your witching hour psyche, tailored to the radio-friendly adult-alternative airwaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bear with me for a moment. In the early 2010s, I consumed stories about others coming of age (to make sense of my own); and around the same time, I was also learning how to write. I learned how to write about emotions and other people and all those other hard-to-describe mundane observations about life that were exploded in magnitude. Exploding those feelings in small spaces is what really good music does. You spend so much of your life thinking and feeling things, and it’s not until you see someone else’s articulation of the same thing—almost, but not quite the same—that empowers you to create your own version of it. I don’t know much about anything, but I’ve at least accrued the vocabulary to start talking about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t really think about this until F+tM started dropping thematic compilations of their discography on Spotify, and I was as blown away hearing “Seven Devils” in 2022 as I was when I first heard it in 2012 (this is also known as an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qmt6l8TwJ8w&quot;&gt;iconic music moment&lt;/a&gt; for the season one finale of &lt;em&gt;Revenge&lt;/em&gt;). Her lyricism is visceral—splices you open and promises flowers will soon grow over the gaping wound—and revels in the sturm und drang of it all. “you are flesh and blood! / and you deserve to be loved and you deserve what you are given / and oh, how much!” is something Whitman wishes he wrote. The snapping violence of “Howl” if Ginsberg wrote under a full moon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The music of Florence + the Machine can only be described as cosmic angst; or a violent opera if the genre suits it. There’s a celestial, yet demonic quality to their songs: of possession and near-ascension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tossed-and-turned&quot;&gt;tossed and turned&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;i-promised-some-people-i-would-write-about-hacky-sack&quot;&gt;i promised some people i would write about hacky sack&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched a game of hacky sack transpire on a winter beach, kindly withdrew my participation, and promised some people I would write about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s something about the physicality of hacky sack—a group game where you a tiny football throw up in the air and a circle of people ritualistic reach out with various limbs and body parts to keep it in flight for as long as possible; the round is over when it finally, devastatingly, falls to the ground—and the socialized practice in an open field that suggests a certain restrained ferality. People lose themselves in it, singularly focused on keeping this tiny capsule of sand in the air. A clumsy life purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody plays hacky sack alone. All for the good of the group. This is not a game for the individual: it emphasizes the collective, and if one falters, so does everyone else. The only person that can be let down in hacky sack is everyone else, suspended in the animation of everyone else’s hushed hopes, that &lt;em&gt;maybe it won’t fall this time.&lt;/em&gt; The stakes are high, and their eyes are watching. Reaching out for it, stretching and scrambling; only for it to flash out of sight. The helpless fanaticism as it falls and the desperate motions to rescue it. Limbs flailing. Controlled spasms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each reset promises a new beginning. If they try a little harder or extend themselves a little further, they’ll make it. Maybe they’ll save it this time. It looks like falling forward or tripping backward; flinging arms and appendages askew for their skin to make contact once again. There’s nothing mechanical in the movements, nothing but an urgent fluidity. They’re not the hero of the story (there are no heroes in hacky sack), but they’re doing enough to keep it alive for a little while longer. Every move is an act of continued salvation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-past-week&quot;&gt;this past week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;watching&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/7Uo2nomf4I0&quot;&gt;tour rajiv surendra’s NYC apartment filled with handmade decor…and chalk art!&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Rajiv Surendra, of Kevin G from &lt;em&gt;Mean Girls&lt;/em&gt; fame, is a modern-day, antique HGTV Renaissance man. He’s a craftsman who can do it all: chalk lettering, calligraphy, bookbinding, pottery, and paper marbling. Just a cool dude who has forsaken expectations of success and bursts with creativity as he does what he loves.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;read&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2022/02/08/sports/olympics/figure-skating-chen-asian-americans.html&quot;&gt;the asian american pipeline in figure skating&lt;/a&gt; by andrew keh
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;not a pipeline&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;listened&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/4X9nSf8xmYbemrz2IAXFgY?si=dbcGwb2kQWKDOteu7bzvMg&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;harder than hell&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, florence + the machine
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;featuring its namesake song, “drumming song,” one of the most visceral songs that ever was&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">collections: a semi-seasonal reset We’re in the double digits now and that’s a modern miracle. I was going to spend this collection writing about something else, but then I read “i can’t stop thinking about this” and, well, these are some things i can’t stop thinking about: in the pantomime: the winter olympics are nothing without canadian ice dancing royalty cosmic operas: florence + the machine lyrics are something else tossed and turned: i promised some people i would write about hacky sack 💌</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">collections — no. 009</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022-01-28/collections-009" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="collections — no. 009" /><published>2022-01-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-01-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022-01-28/collections-009</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022-01-28/collections-009">&lt;h6 id=&quot;collections-a-semi-seasonal-reset&quot;&gt;collections: a semi-seasonal reset&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New year, new letter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you reset for a new year, you have to scrape-off and discard the decayed remainders of the last year. When you’re stripped clean, you’re reminded that there are a few things you still enjoy doing below the caked-on layers of being too busy to do something. I’ve found the temporary vigor to write about nothingness again, and for that I am thankful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;listen up and let me tell you a story:&lt;/strong&gt; six wives reclaim the musical narrative&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the library card&lt;/strong&gt;: plastic keys to an infinite universe&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sunbursts and marble halls&lt;/strong&gt;: your reality is effervescent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;💌&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;listen-up-and-let-me-tell-you-a-story&quot;&gt;listen up and let me tell you a story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;six-wives-reclaim-the-musical-narrative-from-henry-viii&quot;&gt;six wives reclaim the musical narrative from henry viii&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is something truly miraculous about the things you learn in high school. Those formative years cram facts and formulas into your growing brain, some of which will never see the light of day again but a lot of which will resurface in entirely unsuspecting ways. I’ve been listening to the cast recording of &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/5jTDaLFNQovRyjNcWe4cZh?si=L-W_LR1_RAWH5C1fzb8Vhw&quot;&gt;Six: The Musical&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s a time-warp to 16th century England on the stage of Britain’s Got Talent. The Tudors are a fascinating royal dynasty, but it feels a little outlandish to have the full context for the English Reformation in the gossip-drenched pages of the European history book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scene is AP European History, sophomore year of high school. We’re somewhere in the Age of Reformation and transcribing notes from the blackboard on the origin story of the Anglican Church. Top notes of flouting the dominant Catholic order and heart notes of Henry VIII’s uncontrolled libido prompting the union of church and state. For love or whatever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This came shortly after a time when Henry VIII and some of his more infamous wives were all the rage. Henry VIII and the  selfishly mythical love story that surrounds him and formed the Church of England for the allure of a Boleyn girl, swoons historical romance. Trade a country for a woman. The fixation emerges as  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Other_Boleyn_Girl_(2008_film)&quot;&gt;The Other Boleyn Girl&lt;/a&gt; (2008; modern history has entirely forgotten this movie was ever made) and a star-vehicle for Natalie Dormer in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Tudors&quot;&gt;The Tudors&lt;/a&gt; (2007-2010; nobody in real life has ever seen this show but the internet definitely has). The lionization of Henry VIII is mirrored in a fascination with Hades and Persephone: a powerful man can’t have what he wants so he rewrites the rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re not here to do a feminist revision of the Anglican church (though I’m sure John Merriman is not up to that task), even as his six ex-wives have been dignified and denigrated like no others. We get it, six wives is a lot of wives, and we seem to be incapable of moving on from this piece of historical trivia. Things ended terribly for nearly all of them, but especially poor Anne. Anne, a vessel for all the roles she may or may not have occupied in history: Anne Boleyn as the temptress; Anne Boleyn as the wronged woman; Anne Boleyn as the conniving Lady Macbeth. A woman in proximity to power whose story only ends in one way: off with her head. When her head is off, her replacement cycles in with a new wedding ring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to Six: The Musical, a show-stopping riot of songs from the perspective of the ex-wives. It’s bombastic, unapologetic, and deeply empathetic. Henry is Henry, but there are three Catherines, two Annes, and a Jane. Literature loves its alternate-gender perspective retellings, yet this musical is crafted such that it’s less of a retelling and more of a rewriting. By the end, you want the very best for each of them, and truly believe they’re victorious in their own way. The final number pulls a revisionist history and tells their story sans the beheadings and divorces and death. And it’s beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six also turned historemix into a real word, and somewhere out there in the world, Lin Manuel Miranda is picking up another biography at the airport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-library-card&quot;&gt;the library card&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;plastic-keys-to-an-infinite-universe&quot;&gt;plastic keys to an infinite universe&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a small meditation on libraries. I signed up for a library card recently: filled out an application form, handed over my electricity bill as proof of residence, and received a small plastic card in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;eight.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re a kid, the library is a third home. It’s the stop between your actual home, school, and the place you would beg your parents on a free weekend. That’s what my dad would do: he’d use one of his precious days off to drive me to the local library branch and spend most of his afternoon wandering the aisles of international books so I could maximize my precious time in this sacred church. (And when I think about all the things my parents have done for me in the course of my lifetime, I think of these moments. Our tradition of Sundays at the local library. I wonder how different I’d be today if these afternoons never existed). I wasn’t tall enough to look over the library counter, and remember standing on my tip-toes as my dad filled out the application form—and soon, I was handed a card with my name scrawled on the back. It was mine. I would peruse books and stack them high on the ground, adding them to my “check-out” pile; and my heart would skip a beat when I realized a new copy of a book had entered circulation after I exhausted the rest of the series. I’d sign up for a slot at the library computers and indulge myself in a few hours of my favorite sites on high-speed internet: this was my first, enduring taste of the world wide web and the rest of it is simply modern history. You didn’t believe it the first time when you were sitting cross-legged on the reading mat—stringing letters into words and words into new sentences more elaborate than the last—but reading is a lifelong love affair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;fourteen&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re still in school, but decidedly older, the library remains a place in your neighborhood. A permanent fixture that becomes an errand pit stop rather than a full-day destination. I would attempt to maintain a reading habit and occasionally borrow books to sustain keeping up with book series I’d already sunk too much time in. The timbre of this relationship shifts when you no longer discovery books at the library: you become fluent on the ways of the internet and the recommendations it pushes upon you. It tells you if you like this piece of content, you’ll likely like this other thing because other strangers have already connected those dots as data points. This chain reaction is how you cultivate your taste in likes and dislikes. The books you read are the Classics foisted upon you by your beloved English teachers, but also the Contemporaries that teach you how writing lives and breathes in the real world. You begin to disambiguate fiction from nonfiction in craft and form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;nineteen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re a college student, the library is a campus institution. I stopped going to the local library during college. The library became the school library, of which there were many: a landmark of towering marble with cavernous depths, a stout building that rhymed with lament, a remodeled playground whose costs exceeded utility.  The library no longer place of refuge, but a self-flagellating site of misery. You went to the library to study. You stopped by the library for the temporary respite that would enable you to finish homework in-between commitments. You went to the library to hunker down and finish an essay or final project by insulating yourself from the infinite distractions that threatened your productivity. The library was utilitarian and transitory. The environment steeped in the desperation of productivity. “I’m going to the library” as a bad thing, because when you were at the library, you secluded yourself from all the other stuff you could be doing. A hiding place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re older, the library is a mystery. It’s been a while since you’ve visited, properly. You’re in a new city (or maybe the same city), and the library is a place again. You forget that you can simply walk into a library for free during open hours. You’ve come of age in this place: not inside, but of and around it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You notice different things. You no longer fit in at the youth corner (though you’re no less awkward), and meander through the main atrium where the adult books dwell. Books that were once too long and complicated for you to consider. They are primed with best sellers and recommendations from librarians. You trace your finger over a few spines, turn over to the back blurb for another few. You could read all these books if only you had the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re a paltry shell of the voracious reader you once recall. Your reading list expands infinitely, and then collapses into failed mockery at the end of your Goodreads year. You’re awestruck that all these books are real and at your disposal: all you need to do is pluck them off the shelf, walk toward the check-out counter, and return them in two weeks time. In your library-less years, you’ve developed a habit of buying books off Amazon for delivery to your front door, or downloading digital imprints onto iBooks and stealing moments on a commute to read them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something else sharpens into focus of your periphery: all the senior folks sprawled throughout the building. They’re reading newspapers, typing slowly on their small personal computers, half dozed-off in a corner. This is their refuge, where they go to spend their days in the company of words and others. The years blur and you’re suddenly seized with the seismic wonder that children and seniors are one and the same. Kindred spirits who know where they belong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the library’s always been here; you remember that now. It’s been an odyssey, but you’re back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sunbursts-and-marble-halls&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sunbursts and marble halls&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;your-reality-is-effervescent&quot;&gt;your reality is effervescent&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Anne of Green Gables&lt;/em&gt; is my favorite book I’ve never actually read—I do own a paperback copy somewhere, though the spine has never been cracked. I still mourn for the short-lived but brilliant CBC x Netflix adaptation, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/title/80136311&quot;&gt;Anne with an E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;; which I’d recommend to anyone I wish well because these three seasons will make your heart explode in tender happiness. Anne’s story feels so familiar, and I’ve observed her story secondhand so many times that I can describe all the beats of her idyllic Avonlea life. Broken slates and bosom friendships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I could cite my sources and quote some of my favorite writings, they’d sound like echoes of L.M. Montgomery too. A Canadian pastoral that’s really a coming of age story about a young girl with ambitious as far and wide as the open sky and fields before her. Anne (with an E) is and isn’t a stand-in for the dreamers who wish they could keep dreaming, because even when she suffers, she maintains her unrelenting belief in the good of the world molded to her rosy gaze. This girl as she grows up to a young woman as the series evolves, and she’s supported as much as she supports herself in her unflinching faith in &lt;em&gt;Anne&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her story is about having something to believe in, and when there isn’t much of anything else, that something is someone. When Weike Wang &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2022/01/31/the-anne-of-green-gables-vr-experience&quot;&gt;recently reviewed a VR-ified Avonlea&lt;/a&gt; for  &lt;em&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/em&gt;, the review begins to interrogate why we’d put on a headset to transport ourselves to a 19th century Prince Edward Island. It tells a self-insertion narrative that starts at one end, and breaks when things get hard (in this virtual fantastical reality, you can leave when you’re ahead), or persist through to the happy ending (it’s all rather quaint). From here, we draw a connecting line to Jia Tolentino’s &lt;em&gt;Pure Heroines&lt;/em&gt; essay, where young girls are immortalized in the crystal clarity of free spirits in a constrained world. Bright lights that burn to their ends as they age, when they are no longer the heroine in the story. But Anne never loses her light, nor do we ever picture her beyond her early years as a red-headed orphan. That’s where her story starts, and I can tell it to this day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-new-year&quot;&gt;this new year&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;watching&lt;/strong&gt;: euphoria (season 02)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;read&lt;/strong&gt;: “&lt;a href=&quot;https://genyeet.substack.com/p/posting-for-posterity&quot;&gt;posting for posterity&lt;/a&gt;”
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“But mostly, I am learning to let go. I am learning to trust that what matters will stick.”&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;listened&lt;/strong&gt;: del water gap, jeremy zucker (the theme of this is a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; misplaced sad indie boy revival)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(a/n: unintentionally, the first collection of this year revolved around the stories of young women named anne and the place where i likely first encountered those stories. perhaps that’s the theme.)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">collections: a semi-seasonal reset New year, new letter. When you reset for a new year, you have to scrape-off and discard the decayed remainders of the last year. When you’re stripped clean, you’re reminded that there are a few things you still enjoy doing below the caked-on layers of being too busy to do something. I’ve found the temporary vigor to write about nothingness again, and for that I am thankful. listen up and let me tell you a story: six wives reclaim the musical narrative the library card: plastic keys to an infinite universe sunbursts and marble halls: your reality is effervescent 💌</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">past-lives: the year twenty twenty-one</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022-01-23/2021-pastlife" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="past-lives: the year twenty twenty-one" /><published>2022-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022-01-23/2021-pastlife</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022-01-23/2021-pastlife">&lt;p&gt;Last year ruthlessly settled into this year—2022 rolled in and receded a bit, and I finally found a Sunday afternoon to ruminate on the year we just left behind. More than anything, 2021 left us: a once hopeful reprieve that spiraled and thrashed in a final disappearing act. In that year-long unease, &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; is what I read, wrote, did, and resolve to do more of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-year-in-review&quot;&gt;a year in review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2021, I watched thirty-one seasons of tv and twenty-four films; read approximately twelve books; and mindlessly tabulated myself in other ways: like first adult apartment, seven spice jars and fourteen sauce bottles, and six strands of christmas lights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-read&quot;&gt;what i read&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than rehash how I’ve failed my Goodreads reading challenge once again, I’ve sifted through my favorite reads from my Instapaper archive. To know what someone reads is to know how they think; and to know what resonates is to know who they’ll become as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;read: &lt;a href=&quot;https://lighthouse.kellyluo.me/&quot;&gt;lighthouse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-wrote&quot;&gt;what i wrote&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote without any desirable consistency &lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;, but I wrote a few things elsewhere that I’m quite fond of: &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.kellyluo.me/2021-12/on-the-plane-over&quot;&gt;and i was thinking on the drive down&lt;/a&gt; (thoughts about the places we go); &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.kellyluo.me/2021-11/musical-memorabilia&quot;&gt;knowing all the words to your old favorite song&lt;/a&gt; (music and memory, and the passing of time in-between); &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.kellyluo.me/2021-04/collections-006&quot;&gt;fighting fire with fire&lt;/a&gt; (from no. 006, the little fires everywhere in our pandemic year); and &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.kellyluo.me/2021-12/seasons-twenty-one&quot;&gt;seasons mmxxi&lt;/a&gt; (how i actually felt as the seasons changed in the past year).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-did&quot;&gt;what i did&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The true highlights of the past year are documented through digital photos or sharp anecdotes: there’s a lot I did (and didn’t do)—in life, at home, or for work. This, however, is a shrine to all the little things I did for myself that still &lt;em&gt;matter&lt;/em&gt;, but didn’t make it to the front page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I received a boarding pass for my first flight in two years (seat 15C), found a gift card that had been missing since late 2018, and filed my taxes through the grit of self-determination and free tax software. I assembled furniture with my bare hands and a tiny allen wrench, cleaned and tidied as a practice of care rather than an oppression of chore, and spent ridiculous sums of money on storage bins to contain the sprawl of my transposed and newly-acquired possessions. I also started writing &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;collections&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and valiantly continue my attempts to collect myself to write more, set-up my Instapaper and e-mail newsletter-sorting system that feels like the better part of my brain if I actually took the quiet time to read everything I saved-for-later, and collaged my reading highlights into word-panes of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lighthouse.kellyluo.me/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;lighthouse&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I celebrated the end of the &lt;em&gt;To All the Boys&lt;/em&gt; era by writing one last email, reclaimed the songs of my pre-teen days(Taylor’s Version), and even caught up on &lt;em&gt;Succession&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Sex Education&lt;/em&gt; (arriving about three-years late to the cultural phenomenon). I changed my mind about the sprawl and steady influence of the streaming industry, finally understood why cookbook publishing is thriving, and found a faintly-floral fragrance I’m quite satisfied with—apparently maturation is finding appreciation for former derision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-acquired&quot;&gt;what i acquired&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cliché is that no year should end in a bountiful celebration of consumerism, but while the global supply chain had a mild meltdown on open ports, my dwelling became a cavern of hollowed-out cardboard packages. I carried a select few of my worldly posessions across the country and purchased a number of shiny new objects to a fresh address. Possessions have become near and dear since that fateful March—there’s been so little to savor, so few real things to hold onto—that if we can hold onto the material items that spark joy, we can throw everything else into the raging bonfire outside. There’s a lot money can’t buy, but money did buy me some of my favorite things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;for the kitchen: &lt;em&gt;tongs&lt;/em&gt; (guaranteed to compel you to roast vegetables at twice the rate) and a &lt;em&gt;swivel peeler&lt;/em&gt; (knives are hard, okay).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;as many &lt;em&gt;mason jars&lt;/em&gt; as would be appropriate for a circa 2010  suburban homemaking fantasy pinterest board.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the enduring americana icon, the lodge &lt;em&gt;cast iron&lt;/em&gt;. humble, sturdy, and hardy. also makes for an excellent gift.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;this is technically not a purchase since it’s been in my possession for nearly two years, but a &lt;em&gt;plaid-checkered stole&lt;/em&gt; worn for the first time during the early fall, and even though the leaves didn’t change this year, the day felt as crisp as a new england afternoon.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the continuation of (partial) work from home bought me an &lt;em&gt;L-shaped desk&lt;/em&gt; and the separation of physical-digital space has been life-granting.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a 25oz &lt;em&gt;pink prosecco candle&lt;/em&gt; that smells like an expensive holiday ceremony. candle burning as a non-renewable ritual.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;two artificial budget christmas trees (one is adequate, but will never be appropriately enough) and a &lt;em&gt;champagne-colored ornament set&lt;/em&gt; that was upsettingly out of stock later in december.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;as the basis of all foods that need a salty-sweet-spicy kick, an unassailable tub of &lt;em&gt;gochujang.&lt;/em&gt; even better when slathered on foods that pair well with a sheet of &lt;em&gt;nori&lt;/em&gt;. the diet of a meandering cook who reliably grocery shops along a single stretch of japantown.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;painting with &lt;em&gt;butter london nail polish,&lt;/em&gt; a gentler and glossier outfit for my nails.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;finally catching onto the trend of smart &lt;em&gt;color-changing light bulbs&lt;/em&gt; as anyone with agency over their room lighting should do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a series of &lt;em&gt;vintage cavallini decorative posters&lt;/em&gt; in need of proper frames for celebration, printed in vibrant inks and yellowed textured paper, that scale the white walls of my surroundings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;starting afresh with an old &lt;em&gt;dot-grid notebook&lt;/em&gt; to operate my life and abandoning the orchestrations of notion (kindly request that we stop endorsing life OS as a desired object of manifestation).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;alongside the many spice jars and sauces, at least three variations of &lt;em&gt;salt&lt;/em&gt;: kosher, flaky, and iodized table. the past few years have left behind some big wounds to brine.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;random &lt;em&gt;restaurant receipts&lt;/em&gt; from eating outside at new spots and conversing over a shared meal and still talking long after the food is cleared&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; a treasured reminder of what we lost and still have to regain upon return.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and finally, a sense of corporeality. &lt;em&gt;realness&lt;/em&gt;, again. of people. of locations to visit, of places to stay. of time passing too quickly because good things are happening. of interactions and encounters. the easy, familiar ones. the new and awkward ones. the ones still to come.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—inspired by this very good &lt;a href=&quot;https://haleynahman.substack.com/p/79-my-favorite-things&quot;&gt;newsletter about favorite things&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;what i disposed:&lt;/strong&gt; the antonym of acquired ought to be disposed. in fact, I acquired new dislikes as well (and may have been unsuccessful in the dispossession); however, to dwell on dislikes is to poison the marrow of daily existence. the short-list for this would be putrid personality traits, steeply-sloped hills spanning multiple city blocks, abandonment as an antagonist, the new hbomax gossip girl reboot, organic tree-lighting ceremonies, and inertia. that last one, is the one that cannot be moved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-resolve&quot;&gt;what i resolve&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be unkind to make resolutions for the new year, as I’ve unsuccessfully done for so many years in the past. I do, however, have a few themes I’m resolved to continue exploring in the third year of this new decade:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;unlock what makes me tick&lt;/strong&gt;: taking notice of the small things where I’ll go the extra mile, that uplift and delight in opposition to mundanity, and unabashedly wielding these weapons of self-indulgence; things like clever turns of phrase and alliteration, or well-considered artifacts (format and presentation, itself, as a craft), or cultivating an abundance of supply rather than cowering against scarcity. finding the absolute greatest joy in being extra because doing any less would be deflating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;attend the academy of real-life&lt;/strong&gt;: “adult enrichment” is one of the funniest phrases there ever was, advertised as if being an adult were thoroughly devoid of enriching activities and the buck stopped when we last pursued resume-padding extracurriculars in high school; there’s something entirely ridiculous in the notion that learning stopped after that last diploma and tuition debt. there also is, perhaps, an endless queue of subjects I’ve signed myself up to learn under the pretense of inching closer to mastery—such as writing creatively about reality, dissecting and then weaponizing comedy, growing at my job discipline, even working clay on a kiln, and if a future impulse purchase comes to be, melting wax into candles or a driving class for good measure—alongside everything else I’m supposed to learn about living with a newfound modicum of financial independence. doing everything also means doing nothing; life is long and hobbies are a dime a dozen (“so what do you do for fun?”). there are a lot of things I want to do and conquer in the new school of life, and my starting point needs to be simply showing up for class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;making do with what’s here&lt;/strong&gt;: maybe, just maybe, there’s less novelty in racing toward the finish line when the time horizon has moved back by a few dozen decades. this means I’ve been slowly attempting to remind myself into reinforcement: the gift of discontent is to have &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; to start&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; and the courageous disposition to want better for yourself. so stop doing whatever you think will sound good when you say it out loud, and focus on what feels good if you just stopped to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-onwards-to-the-next&quot;&gt;and onwards to the next&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow I think writing this over a span of two months and a long afternoon was an unconsciously proactive attempt at evading nostalgia before it strikes; and writing this year in review was certainly less tumultuous than writing the one from the year before last. But I sense there’s an unrealized mechanism of self-preservation at play here: if I don’t make the conscious effort to concretize the hills and valleys of the last year, the sandstorm will blow through and flatten my memory into soft blurs of a pandemic purgatory. Maybe this will be how I prove to my future self that the current of change carried me through even as time stood still. It’s so easy to forget so much, and these annualized diaristic tendencies keep the topography alive and wild. Over the next year, I’ll capture everything else: what I thought, acquired, valued, and foresaw.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Last year ruthlessly settled into this year—2022 rolled in and receded a bit, and I finally found a Sunday afternoon to ruminate on the year we just left behind. More than anything, 2021 left us: a once hopeful reprieve that spiraled and thrashed in a final disappearing act. In that year-long unease, this is what I read, wrote, did, and resolve to do more of. a year in review In 2021, I watched thirty-one seasons of tv and twenty-four films; read approximately twelve books; and mindlessly tabulated myself in other ways: like first adult apartment, seven spice jars and fourteen sauce bottles, and six strands of christmas lights.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2021, in review</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021-12-31/2021-in-review" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2021, in review" /><published>2021-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021-12-31/2021-in-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021-12-31/2021-in-review">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;an ordered list of things i really loved this year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-summary&quot;&gt;in summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shows:&lt;/strong&gt; thirty-one&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;films&lt;/strong&gt;: twenty-four&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;books&lt;/strong&gt;: twelve-&lt;em&gt;ish&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;audio&lt;/strong&gt;: mostly taylor’s version&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lukewarm disappointments&lt;/strong&gt;: gossip girl (hbo max)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;see &lt;a href=&quot;https://scrapbook.kellyluo.me/archives/2021&quot;&gt;scrapbook 2021&lt;/a&gt; for all the other stories from 2021&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tv-shows&quot;&gt;tv shows&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;thirty-one-tv-shows&quot;&gt;thirty-one tv shows&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;wandavision (jan - mar 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mare of easttown (apr - may 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sex education (sept 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;succession (oct - dec 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the white lotus (aug - sept 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;very-honorable-mentions-for-their-small-screen-debut&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;very honorable mentions for their small-screen debut&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;superstore (s06, jan - mar 2021), loki (june - july 2021), hawkeye (dec 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;films&quot;&gt;films&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;twenty-four-films&quot;&gt;twenty-four films&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;promising young woman (jan 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;spider-man: no way home (dec 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;minari (feb 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;to all the boys: always and forever (feb 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;nomadland (mar 2021; for the oscar win i suppose)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;fashionably-late-to-the-party-with-these-but-also-really-enjoyed&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fashionably late to the party with these, but also really enjoyed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;teen spirit (sept 2021), cruella (sept 2021), home again (may 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;audio&quot;&gt;audio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;dear-2021&quot;&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/playlist/6X519DwhCT1st19zYkdyEc?si=7cb17f3e63b0466c&quot;&gt;dear 2021&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;red (taylor’s version) (nov 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sour, olivia rodrigo (may 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;fearless (taylor’s version) (april 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reads&quot;&gt;reads&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;what-i-read-and-highlighted-from-the-lighthouse&quot;&gt;what i read and highlighted from the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lighthouse.kellyluo.me/&quot;&gt;lighthouse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/03/magazine/steven-yeun.html&quot;&gt;the many lives of steven yeun&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;jay caspian kang interviewed steven yeun on the minari press tour, and i’ll think about this articulation of the asian american experience forever.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Sometimes I wonder if the Asian-American experience is what it’s like when you’re thinking about everyone else, but nobody else is thinking about you,” Yeun said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecut.com/2021/02/tavi-gevinson-britney-spears-was-never-in-control.html&quot;&gt;britney spears was never in control&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;tavi gevinson wrote about britney spears’ conservatorship and the powers forced upon young women&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;At the same time that young women are disadvantaged by age and gender, youth does carry currency, which can be mistaken for power.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://annehelen.substack.com/p/no-im-not-ready&quot;&gt;no i’m not ready&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;anne helen petersen found the words for the one-year grieving exercise we experienced in march&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grief metastasizes when neglected. I have experienced it in the form of full body-wracking sobs when a song comes on the radio, and in dreams I wake up from with tears streaming down my face.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://griefbacon.substack.com/p/thomas-cromwell-is-real-and-strong&quot;&gt;thomas cromwell is real and strong and my friend&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;helena fitzgerald called out calendars for what they are: a coping mechanism for chaos&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;A calendar is a way to invent meaning where there is none and, often, so is a novel, rendering the cluttered events in a human life into a false and singing coherence.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/07/06/magazine/screenshots.html&quot;&gt;screenshots tell the real stories about who we are&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;kyle chayka described the purest form of love and attention on our phones, the humble screenshot&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;And if memories are what make us human, then our screenshots tell a story about who we are in the digital age.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blgtylr.substack.com/p/bobos-in-ikea&quot;&gt;bobos in ikea&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;brandon taylor indicted the examined, zillenial life of posturing for the same few statement pieces&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;A life that is cosmopolitan, which is to say, a life that belongs to no particular space or time, a life that knows no particular geography. There are no more local lives&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://reallifemag.com/nameless-feeling/&quot;&gt;nameless feeling&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;ludwig yeetgenstein articulated that ineffable collection of things we’ve spent all year calling vibes&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;It diverts attention away from narrative and moral implications in favor of foregrounding the idea of affect as inexplicable, ineffable — a matter of chance correlation of elements rather than something that requires deliberate causal explanation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vulture.com/article/gossip-girl-reboot-behind-the-scenes.html&quot;&gt;superrich kids get trolled&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;hunter harris created a behind-the-scenes profile that was the best thing to came out of the new gossip girl reboot nonsense&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The fantasy of the show is that these characters are 17-year-olds who, with the right mix of absentee parents and no credit limits, are allowed to act as adult as they want.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-the-cutting-room-floor&quot;&gt;on the cutting room floor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guilty-pleasures&quot;&gt;guilty pleasures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;things-i-cant-believe-i-watched-but-nobody-is-surprised&quot;&gt;things i can’t believe i watched but nobody is surprised&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the sex lives of college girls (dec 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the voyeurs (sept 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the republic of search (sept 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;beautiful world, where are you; sally rooney (sept 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lukewarm-disappointments&quot;&gt;lukewarm disappointments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;things-i-wanted-to-love-but-really-couldnt-im-sorry&quot;&gt;things i wanted to love but really couldn’t (i’m sorry)&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gossip girl (hbomax, july 2021 / nov 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;solar power, lorde (aug 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hsm : tm :ts (s02, may - july 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;shang-chi (sept 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;icarly (reboot, june 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;predictions-2022-&quot;&gt;predictions 2022 🔮&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;whats-next-year-without-more-media--culture&quot;&gt;what’s next year without more media &amp;amp; culture&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1989 (taylor’s version) (early summer 2022)
if taylor can tour, we get 1989 and a blowout summer album to boot. if she can’t, we’re getting speak now and dear john will shine over many sad empty towns.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;new hozier album, vol.3 (late spring)
it’s about time and we know hozier has been stewing on some sad songs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;persuasion adaptation
in the year 2020, emma. was so stylistic and sumptuous that they simply have to make another for the most heart-wrenching of the austen novels&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;enola holmes sequel
it’s going to be really cotton-candy cute&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;never have i ever, s02 (late summer)
this love triangle is not a triangle, and there really is only one appropriate, definite ending and we are all clear on what that is&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wildcards&lt;/strong&gt;: olivia rodrigo, vol. 2 (fall); harry styles, vol. 3 (late fall/early winter)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">an ordered list of things i really loved this year. in summary shows: thirty-one films: twenty-four books: twelve-ish audio: mostly taylor’s version lukewarm disappointments: gossip girl (hbo max) see scrapbook 2021 for all the other stories from 2021</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">seasons mmxxi</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021-12-30/seasons-twenty-one" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="seasons mmxxi" /><published>2021-12-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021-12-30/seasons-twenty-one</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021-12-30/seasons-twenty-one">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/seasons_twentyone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;seasons twenty-one&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a past-life, I would write a series about the seasons. I’d use those installments to mark the passage of time and wax poetic about the seasons evolving and bleeding into each other. That as one season ended and another began, we’d keep moving forward: because the seasons would keep changing even as we asked (kindly) for it to stop. Each new season beautifully distinct from the last, but resolute in their transient familiarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the twentieth year of the millennia turned into the twenty-first, the days turned into months and the months have become a year and some change. Just like the rest of us, the seasons are scathing, bitter, and weary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read something about the seasons this past year that I’ll think about forever: “&lt;em&gt;the seasons no longer mark the passing of time but various failed bargains with nature.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve failed so many times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;winter&quot;&gt;winter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;h-35f-l-25f--snow-storms&quot;&gt;H: 35°F; L: 25°F | snow storms&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a cold winter. A slog. I was working at five p.m. and all the light would disappear from the sky. It was dark before dusk, and I was deflated. I didn’t know it until the first few days of sun peaked through late February, but it came to me like a full-body restoration. I don’t remember much aside from the brisk cold and the little space heater that kept my room warm through the evenings. There was still no where to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wilted, is the word. To cower in the absence of sun and calciferol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spring&quot;&gt;spring&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;h-82f-l-36f--light-rain&quot;&gt;H: 82°F; L: 36°F | light rain&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt vacant. Hollowed out by the past year: one whole year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few systematic phases to picking up new interests while the world warps in a different direction. I watched &lt;em&gt;Mare of Easttown&lt;/em&gt; and couldn’t recall the last time I felt so enthralled by a show week-to-week. Listened to &lt;em&gt;Sour&lt;/em&gt;, repeatedly, as go the chronicles of teenage angst on a sonic warpath. I found myself eager to write again, but lost that eagerness as soon as we turned the corner on the solstice. I filled this incessant void called time by playing video games and revisited the Pokémon pals of my youth. I took up painting with watercolors, studied up on color theory, and revived pigments from pan-baked slumber with drops of water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summer&quot;&gt;summer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;h-98f-l-72f--high-humidity&quot;&gt;H: 98°F; L: 72°F | high humidity&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was good for a while. I wish it was still as great as I’d hoped at the start. I watched the &lt;em&gt;Gossip Girl&lt;/em&gt; reboot and this was one of many things I would end up disappointed by this summer. I saw people, real people, for the first time in a little over a year. I started reflecting on the pieces of myself I lost while at home, and everything I had to regain by being out and about once again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a warm summer in the city: some days sweltering, other days mellow and baking. It felt ripe for renewal, and I was planning all the could-be of possibility. Planning up until I learned my lesson, once again, that only the best laid plans go astray. By the end of the season, we were once suspended in doubtful animation. Nothing had really changed after all; but the heat had deluded us into a cozy, sun-speckled fantasy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fall&quot;&gt;fall&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;h-70f-l-51f--brisk-chill&quot;&gt;H: 70°F; L: 51°F | brisk chill&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When fall begins, we renew. I was in a different state. I last left off in the middle of stanza, and resumed in a separate paragraph of my life. It wouldn’t be the same this time; it may still be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As things crackled and stirred slowly to life, I wondered if this is what it could have been like all this time. I purchased my apartment essentials, rearranged cheap furniture, and put up postcards on a blank white wall; then went grocery shopping and did all the boring, mundane things you have to do when you’re out on your own. I ate so many bowls of ramen (indoors), with many different people. I listened to &lt;em&gt;Red (Taylor’s Version)&lt;/em&gt; as late autumn hummed along, and it was like coming back to something broken and great again. What was once a crumpled piece of paper smoothed out upon second thought. And it was fine, and it was fun, and it was finally here in some form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seasons didn’t really change this time around; the leaves they stayed on their branches this year. But soon, we broke off into a winter—a preamble to the holidays and next year.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In a past-life, I would write a series about the seasons. I’d use those installments to mark the passage of time and wax poetic about the seasons evolving and bleeding into each other. That as one season ended and another began, we’d keep moving forward: because the seasons would keep changing even as we asked (kindly) for it to stop. Each new season beautifully distinct from the last, but resolute in their transient familiarity. As the twentieth year of the millennia turned into the twenty-first, the days turned into months and the months have become a year and some change. Just like the rest of us, the seasons are scathing, bitter, and weary. I read something about the seasons this past year that I’ll think about forever: “the seasons no longer mark the passing of time but various failed bargains with nature.” I’ve failed so many times.</summary></entry></feed>